When we press on this box it'll spring to all of the corners.
And so let's break down what's exactly happening.
First off we have an arbitrarily sized box and when we press on it it it starts in the top left corner
real move or with some sort of bouncing or spring to the bottom left corner.
So there's a translate.
Why that is happening but not to translate x.
And then once it's in this corner it does a translate X to the bottom right corner and also a spring.
And then as it reaches here it will do a translate y back up and then back to its beginning with a trend
x.
So it seems here that all that's happening is a translate X to all four corners with an arbitrarily
sized box.
So yes this is an animation that I created but it's still beneficial to see an animation broken down
into its pieces.
Another technique we could use is B could record this as a jiff and then we could play it back frame
by frame or blow it up into each particular frame and watch the animation happening and seeing the pieces
of each transition as they happen.