We're going to show how to animate this box to all four corners.
Now we're going to do this dynamically we have to find a width and height.
However we won't go explicitly use 150.
We'll show how to use on layout to stave off the height and the width and then do a dynamic animation
based upon that.
So the first thing we're going to do is get the lay out of Our Square.
So with touchable without feedback it actually does it clone element of the view below and then propagates
the layout from this to this down here.
So rather than adding on layout to our enemy to view we're going to lay out here and we're going to
pass it into a function that functions it'll be called Saved dimensions.
So just to save dimensions here and then go create our function say dimensions and that gets called
with an event that events going to have various properties on it.
The one that we want to look at is the native event layout which is going to provide with height and
the x and y.
However we only care about the width and the height.
So we're going to do is save all this stuff with the native event layout with and then also the height
height because goes native event that layout height.
Now on layout should have the dimensions by the time we went to use it.
However there may be a case where you need to confirm that you have the measurements and in that case
we'd have to get a ref and do a measure call which provides an async callback and it goes and grabs
the lay out for us.
So now we need something to animate.
So we're going to create our state and create an animation and do an animated value x y because we'll
be animating both the X and the y of this particular box.
And so this will actually animate our box.
We need to set up some styling civil say Conte's animated styles sequel to transform and then we'll
use this state animation get translate transform which is our help from method to return an array with
a translate x in A translate y for the x and y of our animation.
Now that we have that created we can go ahead and pass it into our box.
And now it's time to actually animate.
So in here in our star animation which will be triggered when we press on our box we are going to first
get the width and the height of our screen so we can do our calculation of the corners contes width
and height will destructuring it from dimensions get window
and then we will do an animated sequence.
This will be able to allow us to define sequence of the corners that we want to go to.
So we're going to set up an animated sequence which takes an array of animations to execute one at a
time and then we'll call star on it eventually to trigger that.
The first one will set up we'll just two springs so that we don't have to define any particular timing.
So the first one will be going from the left corner to the bottom left corner.
And so that will only involve a translate wise.
That means you only need to animate the animated value x y y property.
So we'll set up animated that spring pass in this state that animation Y then for our configuration
object will say to value.
And this will be the height of the screen minus the dimensions of our box.
So we don't necessarily care what our box is or a height of the box will do our height that we pulled
from our dimensions window minus this dot underscore height.
So even though we only have a single animation we can go and start this and refresh and when we trigger
our box you can see that it springs to the corner and or refresh it to restart it.
So now that we will then animate to the bottom left corner will animate across the screen and that will
be to the bottom right corner and that is in a x translate X movement.
So we then need to modify the animation of X..
Notice that we don't have to continually animate two different values the values are always saved inside
of our animated value x y instance.
So we can continually manipulate them as as we see fit and don't have to control the entire information
every single time.
And by that I mean we don't have to continually animate the Y because we've already animated the Y.
So we can do an animated spring pass in this state to animation.
X and in this case with you to value which will be the width minus the width of our box this stuff with
and give this a refresh trigger it and see that it moved and sprung to the bottom left corner and then
moved over to the right corner.
And finally once we are to this bottom right corner we need to then move ourselves back to the beginning.
So the first thing we need to do is move up to the top right corner and then to the top left corner.
Those are both 00.
So now that our values are saved off in our animation Ammie at x y and then just animate each of those
back to the beginning as we see fit to do an animated spring again passing this Up-State animation y
to value of 0 and then do another one animated that spring state animation X passen are to value of
0.
So that will animate from here to the top right corner and then or X will take us back to the beginning.
So let's say this refresh and we can't execute our animation and watch it's spring now spring back to
0 and then spring back to zero on the x value as well.
This animation is slightly contrived however it shows that whatever it doesn't matter what your your
box is or whatever you're in a meeting you can always grab something dynamic.
You don't necessarily have to define the width and the height of it to have control over how it moves
and how you want to move it across the screen because you can always use on layout and you can always
use measure to grab it even if it's a flex or whatever.
There will always be values that you can grab and determine how you want to control your animation dynamically.