You're going to take a look at how we can rebuild something similar to the Facebook messengers dragon
bullheads.
So here we have a bunch of different heads and we can pick up the first one and we can drag it across
the screen and then the others will trail behind it.
Each one of them will be staggered just slightly behind the previous one and the all ends up at the
same location.
So if we break down what is exactly happening here the first piece we want to look at is that yes there
is a drag that is happening.
And the other elements besides this first one do not appear to be touchable and there is a translate
X and translate Y that is happening.
So that means that we all need to do an estimated value x y for this top head as well as the others
as well.
There is a stagger.
However when we talk about using staggerer with drags we will see that it is not necessarily the most
ideal for draggle animations because of how animator works internally.
So what that means is we'll have to recreate some of the staggerer for those other animated heads behind
it.
We don't see any opacity.
We don't see anything.
We just see a translate X Y as well as a staggered head movement to the exact values that this animation
is moving towards.
Finally when we're talking about drags there's a few things to note.
When you're when you're breaking down a drag animation the first one is does the thing that you have
that you have you're dragging does it stay where it's at.
If it does stay words then we're likely going to be using an extract offset.
And that's going to be in the with the pan response that's going to be in the on Panne responder grant
then for the on panel responder move when you break it down to its drag.
Do you see anything else happening.
If you were just dragging a singular head.
Then we would likely be able to use animated event however because we are seeing multiple animations
happening we're likely going to have to craft our own animated set value for this top head and on the
other animation that's happening behind it.
And then finally when we when we let go what happens so we can see that that nothing particularly happens.
The animations that are set on the heads will continue to move towards the position that we left it.
However that's one thing in the on Penn. responder release that you want to think about is when you
drop your animation.
Look at what happens does this.
When I drop it does it potentially spring to either side like some of the Facebook messenger stuff.
If that doesn't happen then we likely don't have anything in our on Penn. responder.
Now something we could potentially do is change the opacity in the on pain response to grant and then
on the release you know shifted over back to an opacity of one just to provide some user feedback.
However we won't do that but just know that when you're breaking down your animations look for what
happens right when you pick it up.
While you're moving.
And then on release you can kind of break down each particular animation that needs to happen at what
step.