Start with are staggered trackable heads we're going to import an image we're going to import Christophers
you know who is the actual creator of animated but then in to set up some heads on our state.
And so we're just going to set up an image an animated by XYZ so we can control the exact positions
of each of the heads.
And then some text for each image will just out some text and the top one that says drag me.
And then finally our our style sheet will just have a container with aligning our items in the middle.
The heads will be 1880 and a border ages of 40 so that we have a round head and then also we're just
going to add a position absolute.
So these heads are free floating and to center any text in the middle of our images just for the first
one.
But what this is going to do is it's going to create our images free floating so they'll stack on top
of each other.
But because we don't define a left top or bottom or right then these aligned items and justify content
will actually center our drag of bullheads in the middle of the screen.
So the first thing that we noticed in our break down video is that we have to do some sort of drag.
So that means that we're going to set up a pan responder and it's only going to be a single panel responder
for our first top trackable head.
So say this dot pan responder is equal to a pan responder.
And this is just the default you know this element is drag ball and it's always draggle.
We noticed that in our pin responded grant we're going to need to do some extract offsets.
We're going to do some movement here but we didn't see any release animation so we can go ahead and
remove our pen responder release.
So as is typical with a drag animation we're going to need to call extract offset which will take our
Delta values from our gesture state and move them into an offset before our Delta values start overwriting
the estimated value.
And that way we can save off the position that the animation is currently at or the diagonal heads currently
not in our offset however because we have four offsets.
We're going to need to map over all of them and extract the offset of each one so in our on PARASCANDOLA
grant we're going to say this state heads map and we could use a for each year because we're not returning
anything.
But you know map is shorter to type.
We're going to pass an animation.
We're going to we're going to extract animation and this will be our function that we're passing to
our map we're going to grab our animation for each one or animated ex-spy and there were just an animation
extract offset.
So this loop over each one extract the offset and there is currently a bug in animated when we call
extract offset the value is manipulated synchronously and it does not go through value which then would
typically stop any other animation that's happening.
And with that if the animation spring that we're going to use doesn't come to rest for our heads.
And then you kick off a nother animation by pressing on the heads then the animation gets screwed up
and the heads will fly everywhere and then animate spring back to where it's supposed to be.
So to combat this we're just going to do a set value and set the value to x and y of 0.
With animation at set value passenger object X of zero and y of 0 even though extract offset would reset
both x and y to 0 already.
So now for our drag that's actually happening the animated event simply just calls value for both x
and y.
And so that's all we want to do for our first head.
So this state that heads will grab our first one and we'll do get the animation and call set value simply
X and pass an our dx and Y and passing r d y and rather than doing just a gesture state or really care
about is the delta x and Delta y.
So we'll just d structure that right there.
So before we get into doing any of the spring animations or the stagger of the heads what we're going
to do is first we're going to render our heads.
So we're going to do this state heads and we're going to clone it a shallow clone with a slice of zero
and then call a reverse on it before we do our map.
And the reason we're doing this is that the order that you render items in Riak need of matters.
So if we were to render it like this with this one on top what's going to happen is it's going to sit.
It's going to render first and then the other three heads are going to stack on top of it.
So the fourth head will actually prevent us from being able to drag this.
Now you could use the index.
However I'm just going to use the slice reverse here just so that it renders in the correct order in
general.
And now we'll just map over each of our items or each of our heads and we'll get a item.
The index as well as all of the items.
So here is when we're going to determine whether or not we need to add our pan responders to our panhandlers
to the particular image.
So I'll say Konst pan is equal to the index that we're currently at.
And because the image you want to drag is at the end we'll do item's length minus one.
And those items come from this third argument to our callback.
And if it is the last item then we'll just return this stop pan responder pan handlers.
Otherwise we'll just return an empty object so we can just continue our spread on to all of the images.
So now that we have that set up we can do a return and we'll do an animated image because we need to
move things around and use animated values.
We will spread our pan on well specified key index just to remove the error message down below.
However you'd likely want to use an ID for this.
Well then Pastner source which will be item image and then will craft a style Heeres with the style.
And we need to apply our styles dot head which will round our image and then we'll need to craft a dynamic
one and to transform and then with our item that animation will get translate transform to craft that
translate x y for us.
So now that we have all of it all of our images rendering we have the one that we want on top to be
dragged.
We have our extract offset and set value working here.
So now when you refresh we can see that our images are in the middle and then we can also drag this
top one around.
So we've set up the drag for the first item.
However now we need to control our other items to stagger to wherever we're dragging this.
We could add our text that we've defined here.
I'm not going to add them as the child of this of this of the animations in this video but you can put
whatever you want inside of those images.
Now we're going to control our pan respond or move likely you would say let's use animated staggerer
and we'll use an immediate Sagger and see what happens really quick.
So if we were to use animated not stagger what we want to do is get our animations all set up so we'll
say this concert animations Zuccarello this state heads slice and we will ignore the first head because
that's the head that we're dragging and we'll map over and get our animation and we need to switch it
over so we restart that animation.
Arrow function and then we would just turn animated spring and pasan our animation as well as our two
value which you can specify as x Delta X and then r y Delta.
Why.
Because we are doing an animated value x y.
So this is going to craft up an array of spring animations for us to stagger.
Now this would then be passed into animated stagger and let's say you want to stagger 10 milliseconds
in between.
In between each one pass in our animations and then call start.
Now this sounds like it's going to work.
However when we refresh and try dragging.
You can see that only one head is following.
And then they all spring to.
Now the reason that is is that every time we move this this animated Sagger is getting cold again.
Now unlike parallel you can say stop.
What you can say stop together on this one won't stop together.
So basically it's getting 10 milliseconds in and it's triggering the first animated spring we have here.
But then when it's called again it stops all subsequent animations for this second and third head.
And so we basically need to craft our own stagger because this combining all of the animations in a
single Stiger will only work on the first half because the other second and third heads will these and
those animations will be stopped because the pen respond and move gets called on every drag and then
when released there's no more drags the animations complete.
So in order to recreate our animated stagger let's remove our enemies dagger here.
We'll also get the index of our animation to create of our heads and we'll do a sequence with a delay.
So we're going to chunk up each of the animations into their own animated staggered.
So we'll say sequence We'll keep our spring here actually and move this return.
So it's a little bit easier to deal with.
Give us some space and we'll do an animated sequence.
And that takes an array of animation so we'll move this one in here and do some formatting.
And because we want to delay each of the animations by a set amount which is 10 milliseconds we are
saying well use an animated delay and do index times 10 and a comma here and then we'll just call start
on it.
And so this will effectively do the same thing as a stagger will delay a certain amount of time based
upon the head that we're at before we do our spring animation.
And this will then have each of the heads operating on a separate animation.
So once this is called Again each of those will stop and spring to a new location.
However each head will be operating separately so we will get a staggerer to actually happen.
So sometimes with animated you once again line all your animations with a stagger or something.
But sometimes it makes sense and it's required to kind of recreate some of those combined animations
so that the effect will happen as you anticipate.