Rather than breaking down actual tinder and exposing a bunch of people's information we're going to
just focus on the application that we're actually going to build.
Now the first thing that we should do is break down all of the pieces that we see.
We have a card here with some sort of chteaux kind of indicating that there's some depth and then additionally
we have two buttons that you could potentially press and say yes or no to what you're currently looking
at.
This is a very classic drag to make a decision animation.
So in one case you can see that we can drag this card in as we drag it a few things happened one the
card is rotating and the image is fading out.
We can see that the image is slightly fading out and at the same time as we drag to the right there's
some text that's also rotated in the opposite corner of where we're dragging towards that is coming
in.
And it has a opacity as well as a scale that does not appear to be any rotate on it.
Now if we move back here you'll see that the opposite happens for a different corner but a different
text.
When dealing with just your animations.
Make sure to kind of analyze exactly what's happening based upon the direction that you're moving.
So for example US moving up or down in the y direction nothing is actually happening but we move in
the x direction.
We see that that's when effects take place.
It's unlikely that there will be an interpolation off of the animated value x y x value while we drag
also think in terms of interpellation with extrapolate as we move this way.
We see that the rotate is affected.
However after we get to a certain point it does not rotate anymore so there's likely an extrapolate
clamp there.
And same for the left side when dealing with gesture animations.
There are generally three pieces.
The start that Grant on Penn. responded grant which we would typically might call extract offset if
we were to move something and put it there and it would stay the move that there's things happening
on move.
And then the release we can see here that we on release on our release we have a animated effect back
towards the middle so we know that there's going to be a unpin response release.
We know that there's movement happening so we will be doing stuff with her on Panne respond and move.
However it does not seem to be any sort of sticking in our on Pan responder Grant.
There's no animation that happens when we pick this up.
And so we know that we likely won't have an on panderers responder grant to do anything when speed initiate
our first touch.
That's all for when we pick it up and drop it down.
Now what happens if we actually answer a question and see that when we dragged and released.
There was a movement.
We didn't exactly drop it and it didn't stay.
We kind of threw it and it continued on so we know that in our and on Pen respond to release when we
haven't gone a certain distance that it is it will bounce back to the middle.
However if we go a certain distance then there's likely going to be a decay or some sort of philosophy
to make our card move off the screen or move in a particular direction.
Let's reset and we can see that there's one final animation to break down.
When we inspect these two cards you don't see the other card and this one behind it seems to be slightly
smaller so we know that there is a slight scale on that animation or that card back there.
That is keeping it slightly smaller than our front yard.
When we release just watch the card and see what happens we can see that it kind of scaled in from a
smaller spot and had a slight spring animation so we can take a look at that again see the one back
there smaller.
We release it sprung in so we know that with our animation after we make a decision that that card back
there has a scale applied to it and that a spring animation this is happening on it to bounce it into
place.
Overall this is one of the more complex and involved animations just because there's a lot going on
but it makes it easy to kind of dissect each individual action as you're doing it.
So first off we can see that there's nothing happening.
Move drags in particular directions.
Top up and down left and right and then do releases and kind of break down each particular thing that
you know of and map it back to ideas that you know and ative.
So we know that there's going to be panners bonder here.
There's going to be opacity that there's going to be scale once we answer and there's scale right there.
So being able to analyze and write down all these sort of techniques and mapping it back to what you
know how to use an animated will be able to make you break down any animation and rebuild that.