Decision making via swiping cards or some sort of gesture has become ubiquitous on the mobile platform.
We have for cat pictures and we've set up a swipe threshold and this is going to be the direction in
which we swipe that will determine what a decision is.
And then we have some other set up of items to render.
And then finally we have a top and this will hold our content our cards and then we have the bottom
button bar.
Take a look at this.
We have some padding so that it's removed a little bit from the bottom and then some other flex friction
bro and aligning our buttons in the middle.
So as we learned in the break down there's going to be some sort of animated value x y as well as when
the decision is made the opacity will change.
And then there's some sort of animation on the background card that scales in.
So with that that means we're likely going to need three different animated values.
Well set the first one up as animation then animated value x y to store our cards swipe location and
then will also create an opacity one that would just be a normal animated value value and then defaulted
to one with our enemy the value x y set up.
Let's take a look at creating our pan responder.
So we're going to take it will mount this pan responder and there was just run a normal pan responded
creation.
Now because we aren't leaving the card in any particular location then we don't actually need to use
the On Pain responded Grant.
However we will need to do our own parents plan or move and release because the only animations that
we saw were driven based upon the direction that we were driving.
Are X and Y values we can just assume that animated that event will be enough for us.
Person all here and just get access to just your state and they will pipe in DX to this animation X
and then D-y to this animation y.
Now that we have this set up we need to go render some images and we only need to render the first one
and the second one.
So in our top here we're going to say this does state that items slice 0 2 and then will reverse it
so that the first one will be on top because that's the one that we want to provide our gestures to
and then we can map over this which receive our callback function and then we will do structure image
ID and text from our array of items here.
We'll also get access to the index and the items in total from here will want to build out our view
our cars.
So without doing any sort of animations or anything we're going to create an animated view close that
off and then we're going out to do an image so say animated image and we'll pass and this source be
our image and we'll get it resized mode cover and then below our image we want to display some text
screen to say view
then here we can do text and pass in our text.
Close that off and then we'll provide our key to the outside animated view which will be our idea.
It's just one two three four but we could use the index in that case.
But when doing this kind of stuff we want to provide some sort of unique identifier that isn't the index.
And the reason why that is in this case is that the indexes are either going to be 0 or 1 and we want
this to be unique.
So when a vendor happens that this actually will get unmounted and change otherwise it will continue
and there may be issues with the image not changing so we will need to style some of this stuff.
And so we're going to start by just applying some styles and say style equals style card.
And then we're also going to need to style him insurance's style equals styles image.
And any time I have an animated view or an animated image or anything that's animated I always just
default to adding an array because I know that I'm likely going to be putting in animated styles and
dynamically and then down here you can say style equals style start lower text.
Now that we've applied our style names now we can go actually build out the styles.
So the first one is card and we're going to give it with 300 a height of 300 and then position absolute
We won't give it any left top right or bottom.
And that way it will adhere to the line item and just have a content of center.
And then we'll go a border radius of three and then apply some shadow so shadow color just be black
shadow opacity will be point 1.
Our Shadow offset will be 0 and y zero.
And then our shadow radius be 5 then we'll also add a border with 1 and a border color of white.
So as we move along you can always refresh this as much as you want and see exactly what's being created.
And we can see that this is not ideal because our image is very big.
So we have a style that next and we'll just override the width to know the height to know.
So that way we can apply a flex property to make it adhere to the with that flexible defined sort of
say flex of three so that the image is three times as big as our lower text when we define that.
And then we'll go to a border radius of two and then for our lower text when you say flex 1 and then
a background color of white and then of hatting of five on all sides.
Now we can refresh this and we now have our card lay out with our images correctly sized in our text
taking up one third the space that's over here and we are ready to start dragging now.
So let's come back to render and we're going to set up our interpolations first.
So we're going to say Konst animation equals this Stut state so we can always just reference our animation
and then we're just fine our rotate for our card say animation X because it's all driven off of the
x axis say Dot and interpolate and then we're going to define our input range in our input range is
going to need to be negative which is when you swipe to the left and then also positive when you swipe
to the right and then net zero will be our stationary position.
So going to the input range negative 200.
So once the user has swiped this direction 200 will reach its maximum rotation zero will be stable and
then 200 will be the maximum on the right side.
Now we can put our output range to be negative 30 degrees zero degrees and then 30 degrees.
And so it does not continue to rotate past 30 degrees will do and extrapolate clamp the next one will
be our opacity sort of say Konst opacity.
See what the animation that exed interpolate and we'll do a similar input range.
We're just going to do a negative 200 0 and 200 and then adjust our output range.
So our output range will be point five one and point five.
And then we can also do an extrapolate clamp here if we don't want our opacity to go anywhere beyond
50 percent.
And now that we have or rotate and our opacity which are two of the animations for the card we can then
build out our animated cards stylings.
So this opacity actually will drive the image styling whereas the opacity of the card itself fading
out all of it will be driven by this opacity that we created right here.
So let's put out both the card styles and the image stylus windsock Konst animated card styles.
It's going to be our opacity with that state opacity.
And then our transform and inside of here we're going to spread our state.
Animation does get translate transform and this will return our translate X translate y former animated
value x y and then we're also going to add our rotate and then with this opacity here we're going to
set up our Konst animated image styles and pass in opacity.
So if we come down for our render to apply it we're looping over the two cards.
And so we need to know exactly which card we're looking at whether it's the front card or the back card.
So we're going to define some helpers for us to say Konst is last item and we're in index equal to item
stat length minus 1 or if it's the second to last
going to say Index items that length minus 2.
Now we only have 2 cards so it's either going to be this is the top card or this is going to be the
back card.
But if we potentially had more cards we would only want to control the the first and the last potentially.
But this is just going to help us do a front item back item.
So now we can determine a couple of different things.
One our panhandlers to the card style and then three the image style.
So we're going to say Konst panhandlers and is equal to.
If it's the last item then I will say this pan responder dot pan handlers or we're just sort of turn
an object and that way we can just continue to do a spread on every card and the first card it's in
front will always receive the panhandlers and we're going to say cants cards style is equal to if it's
the last item or the one in front.
Animated card styles that we just created.
Otherwise undefined.
And finally our image style is the same thing animated image styles that we set up or undefined.
And now with these three variables set up we can go ahead and start applying them so we can do a spread
here of our panhandlers.
So now we're able to drag.
We'll then also pass in our animated card style so our rotate and our translate X Y will be applied.
And then here we will apply our image style.
So let's switch this back to card style because that way it's only being applied from this variable
here.
And now we are set up to refresh.
And now if you start dragging and see that our interpretations are taking effect on just this front
card and our pin handlers are working and you can actually drop that because we have not set up our
on Pan respond to release yet.
So before we get to our release you can see that this card back here is exactly the same size as this
front one and we actually wanted this one to be a little smaller with some scale so that when we make
a decision that this springs forward.
So that means that we need to go set up a nother animated value or just call it next to an animated
value and we're going to default at two point nine.
And with that we can then come down to render here.
And we can use our second to last or is this one in the back essentially and say Konst next style.
Equals is second to last.
And if it is then we will return it transform with a scale and this dot next.
So this at state DOT next.
Otherwise it'll be undefined.
And then we can now take that next and pass it into our card.
And so if we refresh we can see that now that card is just slightly smaller because it is scaled 2.9
the size of its actual size.
So with our drag in place and our next style being applied to the back card we can start we can start
actually deriving what to do in the on and pander on Pan responder least we can derive the decision
that is being made in our pan responder at least we get access to a few different variables on our gesture
state.
We know that the delta x is there and that's the thing that we care about.
We also want to get access to the velocity on the extraction and the velocity in the wind direction
and that will help us do a decay when we swipe and release or if it hasn't gone far enough then we can
actually bounce it back to the center.
So we're going to say let velocity and we're not going to assign it to anything.
And if we have a velocity that is greater or equal to zero then it's moving in a positive direction
to the right else.
If we have a velocity that is less than zero.
Then we know that it's moving in a negative direction and that way we can use our clamp that we we had
about above so that we don't define a velocity that just throws it way off the page.
And so we're going to say velocity is equal to clamp and where it's a velocity x and it's going to have
a minimum of five and a mat or a minimum of three and a maximum of five.
And then for here we'll do the same thing.
Velocity is equal to clamp and we're going to get the absolute value of our velocity.
And then 3 5 and it is going to multiply by negative ones so we get a negative number again.
And so with that you can now say if our math absolute of our Delta X so that's as far as the card has
been dragged is greater than our Swype threshold.
Then we will make a decision.
Otherwise we will spring back to middle.
So let's do our animated spring first and say this state animation and our two value will be zero and
zero.
So we can just reset it and the friction will drop to 4.
And now if we refresh and kind of drag this card and we haven't gone far enough and we released we can
see that it will spring back to its original position.
Now if we have met our threshold then we will consider it a throw and use animated to K to move it to
its final resting spot.
So say this state animation and we'll say velocity is going to be X which is going to be our velocity
x and then WHY would just be R V Y.
And then we will set our deceleration to point 9:8 which I believe is the default.
And then we'll call start.
So now we refresh and we move past our threshold and see that it will end up moving correctly and decaying
all the way until its final position to make our decision.
We need to call a function here after the start has happened.
However we want to make sure that we can actually reuse this same transition for when you press either
the yes or no buttons down here.
So we're going to set up a function called Transition next
and this will transition the cards from the current card to the next card and control all of the animations
as well as the popping of the arrays so because we want to remove the top card from our animation or
from our array we're going to just do a steady state and then both say we'll make this an update or
function because are going to reference our previous state and say return items is going to be equal
to the state that item's removing the first one.
So now that we have this function set up we can just pass that into our decision.
So there's that transition next.
So this will be the callback of Whenever we've made our decision and it hits its final resting place.
And if we refresh this and we swipe we can see that it does in fact rotate but a very jarring fashion.
So in order to kind of fix that jarring animation we're going to do a couple of different things.
One when the decision is made we're going to first do the opacity fade on the dragged card the main
card and then also spring in that second card before we swap it.
So that means we're going to need to do an animated parallel to receive that array of our animations
so that opacity to value of zero.
Because we animate our main card out over the course of 300 milliseconds and then we're also just going
to spring that card into place animated that spring.
This testate next to value of one with a friction of four.
And now we can call start passing our callback so that the animations are completed before we transition
our card.
So let's refresh and see what happens when we answer this question.
All right.
Cool.
So that is kind of working.
But the problem is is that we haven't actually reset our animations so it transitioned cards.
But the next card which was the other cat is now thrown off the page.
So we now need to transition and then reset all of our animations.
And so we can do that in our component update function of that state.
So we need to reset the opacity to one the next scale back to point nine.
And then also the animated value x y back to zeros.
So that way it just resets us to a clean slate ready to be dragged again.
So when you say this that state next set value point nine and we don't need to animate anything we just
need to reset it as quickly as possible and say this that state that opacity set value one and then
we'll set our animation to x zero and y zero.
So now we refresh and we throw our card that fades in and then bounces and then our animation is reset
and there's no other card that is seen except for that and back there which is now our next card.
So we continue throw it and throw it and have our animations take effect and then reset immediately.
So now let's add our buttons and because we have this transition too the next thing we can use this
when our buttons are pressed.
And so let's come down here and in our button bar I'm just going to paste in a couple of buttons and
then we'll go adjust the styling.
Someone will say no and then we'll say yes and now add some styling so we just have a general button.
And then the shadow color for our buttons will be different colors.
So for the red for the No it will be red color and for the yes it will be a green color and these we'll
call are handled now or handle Yes.
So that's set those up and see what that looks like.
So crate handle no and handle Yes.
So the idea here is that just because we are driving an animated value x y based upon an animated event
does not mean that we can't independently control it with a separate animation.
So for example we want to do a a movement of the X to either yes direction or no direction.
We can just use animated timing or spring and animate this state to animation X and we can do it to
value and when it's no mean to say negative Swype threshold and then start it and then transition to
the next card.
And we can do the same thing for the yes and just go to the Swype threshold.
And because we're doing an interpellation based upon the X we can just animate the X.
So now when we refresh and we press on one of these buttons you'll see it rotate and move to each direction
and then trigger our transition next call
to one final piece that we're missing is the Knope and the yes.
And I'm just going to add those because they don't really matter.
But if we paste them in here we want to only show them on this front card and add some styling and some
animation to that because we want to have it scale and fade in.
And so we can take and do an interpolation based upon the x axis just like we've done of our others
so let's do this really quickly.
We're going to get the opacity based upon the X and our input range is 150 with an output of zero to
1 and then we're also going to do a scale.
I'm going to start at point 5 and then move towards a scale of 1 and then also we'll build up our animated
styles with our scale and we'll just define a generic rotate of negative 30 and then our opacity and
then the no version of that is the exact opposite.
So now if we refresh as we swipe in a direction
we can see that we have a Yup there you see it below but we haven't yet styled it.
So if we go look at what styles to apply it's our Yup and nope and we can just go apply those here.
We're just going to add a border and a width and position the text and the view in either the top left
corner or the top right corner depending on which direction we're going.
We just swap out right or left.
And now for refresh we drag and see it so it fades in from a scale of point five and opacity to complete
and then the other direction.
The same thing.
So the key takeaways with doing these decision drags is for the most part all you have to do is in your
on Pan respond to release based upon the either or distance that has been dragged in a particular direction.
You can then derive actions to be taken whether it's resetting the animation or doing a decay to do
a throw.
And then once that animation is complete you can do a transition next which includes are more animations
but also state to set up the next drag or to set up the next few.