Some common animations that occur are on Mount animations so basically animation happens to kind of
focus your attention on a particular item of importance to this happens in Google now cards or in some
cases form fields like we have here.
So now if we refresh and see that each of these staggers in its opacity and has a slight movement one
of my favorite features is the zoom feature the access feature on Mac.
So we're going to zoom zoom in on our form field and then when we refresh can see that there is a slight
movement we start up here.
And then it animates down about five or so offset.
So in terms of a breakdown each of these could be an interpolation but we'll set it up as each individual
estimated values so we can use daggar.
And then it looks like there might be an interpolation on the zero to one of the animation that offsets
each of these about five and then transitions.
And that's a saw common technique is you set up your thing using lay out and then you set values that
will offset it to begin and then animate it back in.
And that way you don't have to control the positioning of your of your item you just let the layout
take effect and user translates to offset it correctly.