For are staggered form fields will only go over the animations and not the lay out of our screen here.
However we'll run through it really quickly.
We have a container in our image background with an absolute fill and A with a height and also that
the image is sized correctly.
We then have a view here and a view here.
Those views are flex 1 and that way we have spacing exactly the same spacing for our view in the middle.
Now we're using a keyboard avoiding view.
Not a big fan of this but we're going to use it so that when we focus on a particular form in this case
we have a command K to open up our keyboard that it will actually move this form correctly so that we
can access the email the password and the logon button which is important for accessibility and just
not pissing off your users in terms of things that we needed to do.
We needed to create an animated text input for both of these because we'll be animating those.
And then additionally we're going to get a ref to our animated text input that we want to focus first.
So that way once our animation is complete we can focus on this email field and then the keyboard will
come up.
Rather than focusing and having the keyword come up during the animation and then finally we just have
a touch for opacity button that doesn't do too much in terms of styling.
You can take a look at the styling here.
We just have a background color on our form that is a dark with a 25 percent opacity.
So you can see the background and have a slight focus on our field content.
Now each of these inputs and button will need their own animated values so we're going to set up our
state and we'll have an email and I a value of zero a password
with another estimated value and that our button with an estimated value because each of the animations
are going to be exactly the same.
We can take make a function that takes an animated value and return styling that we are render stays
kind of clean so we can go out and set up a contest create animation style which will take an animation
and then return some styling for us so because we know that our animation is going from 0 to 1 we can
return a style with our opacity because that was a part of the breakdown with our animation so that
way and 0 to 1 on the opacity.
However with our translator why we're going to need to do a interpellation.
So say Conte's translate why and then animation interpret
and because we're going from 0 to 1 we need to start slightly higher and animate to zero offset.
So the output range which will be negative 5 so it offsets at 5.
Just start and then animate to a zero offset then we can pass that into a transform where that translate
y as our only transform So now that we have our transform all set up we can create each style so we
see Konst email style so you can create animation style and we're just passing this email then do the
same for the others.
This app password stylo.
So you could create animation style the state password.
And then finally button style to go create animation style of this state.
But we already have a bunch of stuff set up so we can go down here and say email style and pass in our
email style.
Same goes for our password style.
And then we'll pass in a button style.
Do note that this is kind of unnecessary touchable opacity uses an animated view behind it.
So we could pass on our button south here in this view animated views kind of unnecessary because you
could style or touchable opacity but we'll add an animated view here to be explicit about what we are
creating and styling.
So now we have our defaults to zero and our animations are being created.
So now if we refresh nothings in a show up because everything is at a zero opacity with a slight offset.
So let's do our mounting animation and to do that we'll use the component did MT lifecycle method inside
of re-act will use the animated stagger so that way we don't have to craft our own Stiger.
We'll do a staggerer which the first argument is the staggerer between each animation and I would say
100 milliseconds.
And then it takes our array of animations we'll just do animated timings over a set duration so they
are animated that timing passen or this state e-mail because that's the first one that we want to animate
to value of one.
And then a duration of two hundred will then call start.
Be sure to pass our callback here so that we can know exactly when we need to focus on our e-mail input
and we'll give this a go will refresh see that it had the appropriate animation.
So we'll start adding in the rest of ours.
So we'll do an animated timing this state password to a value of one duration.
Two hundred and you could create separate animations or different animations for each of these.
We're just going to keep them all the same.
All right so now we have all of our animations set up we should be able to refresh this and have them
all fade in and I make a slight transition translate down.
The only other thing that we need to be concerned about is focusing on that e-mail input.
We want to give the user the keyboard pop up and be able to type the stuff immediately without having
to have them do a separate tap to focus on the appropriate field so we can do that by saying this underscore
e-mail and because we use that create animated component call to wrap our text input to get access to
the actual text input so we can call focus.
We need to use the got to get node data access the the node the actual text but text input node.
And then we'll call focus.
So if I refresh and let me toggle the the keyboard here and refresh again I can see that we animated
in and then our keyboards split up and with a keyboard inverting view we can still see all of the content.