Let's take a look at this animation we have a button and when we press on that button there is an animation
that takes in effect in the background and it has b inside the button and in between the text and the
background of the button.
In terms of a breakdown we can see that there's likely a single animated value that's animating from
say 0 to 1 and that is having an interpolation for a different view that covers the background here.
Then we can see that there is a with interpellation and likely we have a view that is top left and bottom
of the zero and then we interpolate the with and then at the very end we can see that it fades out.
So that's likely going to be a secondary animation an animated value.
So there's actually two animated values here.
One for the background color and the width and then a second to execute after the animation is completed.
To fade out that particular progress bar.