The first thing you're going to do is define our animated value so say state equals animation animated
value that defaults to zero.
This will control the animation for the color as well as the progress of the width across the screen.
Rather than diving into animating this value from 0 to 1 using a timing Lets first set up the progress
bar and the interpellation so that we can see the effect when it happens.
So let's come down to surrender and set up a progress inside of our button.
We have a button here and our text here.
And so in our break time we can see that the progress needs to happen before the button text.
Otherwise if we put it after the button text as the background animated our button text would get covered
up.
So we're going to say View style equals style sheet.
Absolute fill.
This is a helper function for us that does position.
Absolute left top right and bottom zero.
It's just going to define a view that covers this entire thing so that when we use our with percentages
that it doesn't overflow outside of here.
And now with that set up we can set of our animated view and give it a style is styles that progress
which we will go set up.
Now this will be our progress bar.
So we want it to be absolutely positions
and then we want it to be left and top zero.
This will then allow us to control whether or not we want an animation to go left and right from top
to bottom or just cover the bottom of the screen and we'll change those animations later.
So it was a top zero and left zero with that set up.
We're able to now go put build our progress style so our progress style consists of a interpolate on
the percentage.
So will say this that state animation interpret the input range 0 to 1 output range will be zero 0 percent
to 100 percent.
And then we will do an extrapolate clamp here in case 0.
The animation goes beyond 0 or 1.
We don't want this going to be a negative percentage or a percentage over 100.
We'll then set up our background color and templates for sequence color and interpolate to this state
that information interpolate armpit range is going to be 0 to 1 again.
And then our output range is going to be 2.
RG be colors these colors can be whatever you want as long as they are G-B R-Ga. or HGL so that interpellation
will work on them.
Now with these two values set up we can set up our progress task to say Konst progress style and we'll
give our with with our progress interpolate which will be between 0 percent and 100 percent.
We'll then have a bottom of zero for this particular animation.
So now we have our lefts and top applied styles up progress and now we'll just apply a bottom here so
that as our percentage our animation will go across this button and then we'll pass it back on color
with our color and interpolate past this and to our progress bar.
And now it started on what happens when we actually press our button in real life.
This is going to be controlled by some sort of a sink progress operation that you have going.
So when the user presses on this button again we're just going to reset everything and restart our animation.
This kind of is up to you on implementation.
So we're going to do is say this state animation set value of 0 and then will trigger our animation
our animated timing so animated timing pass and this state animation to value of one.
I'll just give it a duration of 1300 milliseconds and then we'll call start.
If this were a real implementation you might do an animated timing and set the value to whatever the
percentages would be like point for point five point six and you're continually triggered this animated
timing over a smaller amount.
But we're just going to animate it to one.
So now when we refresh this and we click on our button we can see that our animation is taking effect
but nothing happens when the button is completed.
We don't have a opacity yet.
So to do our opacity will first set up another animated value to animated value with a default of one
because we want the bar to be visible when we first operate across the screen.
And then once completed fade out.
So then we'll come down here to our progress style and apply our opacity.
So this state that opacity and then inside of our timing will need to specify a callback which its first
argument is an object with finished.
True or false.
If we have finished and we weren't interrupted by another press we'll say animated timing state or past
city and our value will go from one to zero settle fade out over a duration of 200 milliseconds.
OK I'll start on this.
Now to also reset this value back to one we're going to need to do this state animation or this state
that opacity that set value to its default of one.
Now we can go ahead and refresh this.
And when we press on our button will see our animation go across the screen and then fade up.
And then any time it stays in that particular setting and then any time we want to press on this again
our values will reset right before we start doing our timing and our opacity again.
So we can click on it and see that it reset.
So we don't want to do an animated timing on this zero back to here on this you want to watch this Doraine
but that's not what we're setting up now because we're working with a with a percentage that doesn't
necessarily apply to just with it could apply to height.
So depending on the animation that you want we can pass these in and modify our style slightly to get
some different animations.
So rather than setting a bottom of zero if we change this to right and rather then with the progress
we change it to height.
But that's going to set up as a left and top of 0 and then all the way over here.
So basically the animation will start up here and then animate to the full height.
So if we refresh this and we press on it again we see that it animates in a curtain style and then finally
because we've passed this progress stylin as the second parameter we can override styles in the styles
that progress.
So if we wanted this to be a small bar on the bottom of our button will change us back to with of with
the progress then we'll switch over to the top.
No because we don't want it to be on top anymore you want it to be on the bottom and that will move
our bar to the left bottom and then animate all the way to the right side.
Now we do need to add a height and this height will just be five.
It could be any value but that will be a five pixel bar on the bottom here.
So if you refresh and sugar are animation that we now have a bar that just animates along the bottom.
And finally if we didn't want any particular color we can remove this and remove our top notch and keep
our progress and serve plate.
And rather than our color inter-relate we can just pass in a background color that's R-GA to 55 to 45
to 55.
So white with a point five opacity and this will allow a kind of whitish background to go across the
screen.
So this will just ignore color interplay because we're passing in a background color and we refresh
this and trigger our button and we just see a white ish background go across the screen or across the
button.