This is an animated questionnaire and we'll see that when we press on any of these.
We animate one question out and one question in and then additionally we see that a progress bar happens
down here
in terms of a break down to animated values and effects that are happening just translate why that's
happening.
So this one is moving off screen.
And then there's another one like the running of over here that's translating in and then a swap will
happen once this translates into who you can see that an animation will take this one off the screen
while another one comes in and then we can swap it and put the information that came from over here
right here and then render our next question to answer over here.
Now the progress bar is probably just interpretating off of the number of questions asked for a with
and so we can do all of this with a single animated value and then we can see what happens when you
press X and then everything just resets instantly.
Yes no yes yes.
And animate all of our questions out of the way.
The idea for this animation and inspiration came from you eye movement which links to the original source
which is Robbie Pierce on dribble and an easy way to check out any animation a breakdown of the animation
is to open it up in Preview.
So if we open up our shift it takes each Jiff and breaks it down frame by frame.
And so you can you can step through the frames and actually see the transitions that are happening.
So when you press on the yes we see that a slight opacity is changing and we can watch as each frame
happens.
So we see that in this frame we know that two questions are rendered at the same time because we have
one here and then we can see the second one coming into frame and then we can see it move over and sit
in its final position.
And this is just an easy way to see each frame by frame.
You don't have to look at all of them but for a given frame you can see what exactly is happening and
what sort of effects you need to recreate.