Get this questionnaire we're going to start with just an array of questions and an empty render.
We first need to do a little bit of setup before we can start.
So the first thing we're going to do is have two buttons at it.
So we'll say touchable opacity and on press we'll just say this handle answer and this is we do our
animation and we'll give it an active opacity of point 7.
And inside of our touchable opacity we'll just give it some text say text and no and we'll do the same
thing for our.
Yes.
So we'll copy this and create a yes button.
Now when we refresh we see that we have a no and a yes here.
However we are know to be on this side and are yes to be on this side.
Because we want our buttons split down the middle in a row fashion.
That means our container is going to mean to be a just to flex direction of row for refreshes.
We can now see that there is it is in a row kind of under here but let's fix that with our option.
So this will be a yes or no.
It'll apply to both.
So this option styling will be applied to both of our buttons so we want it to stretch the entire way
so will say flex 1.
We want our content to be at the end so we'll say justify content flex and and then we want our content
to be centered inside of our container so say a line items center.
Now if we take our option style and we apply it to our touchable opacity and here as well were refreshed
you can see we've moved our buttons to half and half flex and end centered.
Now for our final styling on these buttons we're going to create some option text dialing and we'll
just get a font size 30 color of white and then we'll just get a margin bottom of 50 to remove it here
up off the bot bottom a little bit.
Yes.
Styling just to be able to distinguish between each buttons say background color or G.P.A. 255 255 255
and point 1.
Now in refresh.
Nothing happens because we haven't applied our styles yet so let's apply those our Yes some styling
and then our text him style style equals styles that option text and then Same here
now refresh we have yes or no moved up slightly.
And our Yes has a slight cover over it so we can distinguish between presses now that we have our buttons
rendering.
Now we need to render our questions so we need to be able to operate independently of this particular
layout here.
So we're going to you could have you and we're going to give it the stylesheet absolute fill and that
way it'll be a view that just covers this entire container so we can work with it.
The other thing we then needs to do is add our questions.
However we don't know what questions we need to render and that's where we have this index on stay here.
You can derive which questions we need to render will render to questions will render the first question
as the main question and then a second question that will sit off screen that way we can animate one
off.
And the second and at the same time say say conc question which be our main question will be questions
index.
And then we need to do some slight Figuring out of arrays so is the next question.
And then if our index that we currently have selected plus 1 is less than questions length.
So if the next question is inside of our range then will say next question is equal to questions.
Index plus 1.
This way we just grab two of the questions the current one and the next one if it exists.
So how this concept is going to go is that we need to center our questions in the middle of the screen.
And then they have to be on the same plane.
So what that means is that when we render one question and we animate our second in when we re render
with the next question as the main question and needs to be in the exact same spot.
So that means that we were we are going to have to do some absolute positioning to determine to make
the items flow correctly to make the text flow correctly.
Now before we move on we do need to come up here and do structure questions and index from this state
so that we can reference them as normal variables and now we can start laying out our views.
So what we need to do is render our questions so animated that text because we will need to animate
the questions via translator later.
So our first question close off that and then render our second question
which is our next question.
And then close that off and then refresh we can see that they are rendering one on top of each other.
But we want them in the middle of the screen so to get them there.
Lets apply a tile here which would just call styles overlay and will come create our overlay style which
would just be a line items center and justify content center.
So when we refresh we now have to have our questions in the middle of the screen.
Now these questions are stacked one on top of each other.
But we want their layout to be independent so we can position them how we feel.
So let's create a question text and we will do a background color of transparent to start then we will
do a position absolute.
So that way each of their questions is free floating.
Well then give it some font size a 30 color of white and then we also do text align center to the text
justified to the middle and then we have our question textile and we can go ahead and apply it to our
questions.
So just style equals and we are going to use an array here because we are going to have to animate later
as well to duplicate multiple styles to animated text so we'll pass that in here.
And then apply over here as well.
Step one to refresh.
We can see that the two questions are sitting right on top of each other.
And now comes the actual animation sort to come up here on our state and we're going to create our animation
and create a new animated value and set it to zero.
And what we need to do with this and render is have our main question sit at zero.
And when our animation happens you'll move it to the left and at the same time we need this one to sit
off screen and move at the same time into frame.
So to do that we're going to need to use some interpellation.
So we're going to first get the width of our screen so we're going to restructure off of our window
and then we'll set up to interpellation the first will be our Konst main question and chirpily and this
will be this state that animation inter-relate and our input range will just be zero to one in our output
range which will be fed into our translate X will be the negative it will be zero because when we are
zero like we are here we don't want it to move anywhere.
And then we will set it up to negative with that way it will completely translate the entire width over
here.
Then for our next question will do cance next question.
Inter-relate will then be at state animation to interpret the same thing and put range of 0 and 1 ever
at zero.
We want it to be offset the entire width over here.
And that's because we have our style sheet to fill that takes up the entire screen.
And so we'll set it at 0 will set it to with and then as we move towards 1 will animate the translated
view over here and be in frame.
So this one main question out at the same time our second question will intimate in and now we just
need to craft our styling so essay contest Maine style is equal to transform takes in objects an array
of objects translate X and fast.
And our main question and interpolate.
And then do the same thing for our conc next style transform
translate X and pass it.
Our next question interpolate.
Now these two can be passed into the animated teks main style and next style.
And now if we refresh this our first question is here and our next question is now translated away off
the screen.
Now let's go see what happens when we trigger our handle.
Answer the first thing that we will do is create a handle answer.
And because we don't care what the answer is we're just going to do the same animation.
So say animated timing this state animation to value of one with the duration of four hundred milliseconds
and then call start.
So if we refreshed this we can now answer a question and it will translate that question off and this
question on at the same time.
However we aren't doing any sort of transition of this index because remember our questions are run
based upon this particular index.
So in our start we'll need to take a call back here and then do this set state and because we will reference
our previous state we'll need to do an update or function and then return a new object with index and
state index plus 1.
So when our animation is completed we will flip over to me the main question.
Well now the next question will now be the main question and we'll have a new next question.
But then we also realized that the animated value for this animation is still at one and we don't want
that because that would then have the next question be translated way off stream stream screen because
it became the main question.
So then in our component did update callback to set state will then do this start state that animation
does set value back to zero so we can go ahead and refresh this now.
And when we press on an answer this animated then we changed the animation and reset this.
So now we have a second question off screen and we can prove that by pressing another answer and then
another answer as well.
It's very important to understand the callbacks that animated provides as well as what set state and
reac provides in terms of callbacks.
It allows us to set up and adjust our animations and prepare for new animations.
So one final bit is our progress bar.
So let's go ahead and set that up here.
We'll do a view which is a style the styles styles progress.
And then inside of that we'll set up an animated view which would be our progress bar say animated view
in style equals styles up bar close it off.
Now let's set up our styling for our progress and progress bar for our progress.
We'll have it on the bottom of the screen.
So when you do position absolute It will be left zero bottom zero right zero.
And then we'll just give it a height of 10.
And then for our bar rather than given an explicit height of 10 we'll give it a height of 100 percent
and then a background color of white.
Now because this is operating independently of our main question which is just anything from 0 to 1
we'll need to set up a second progress animated value.
So say progress here animated Valley just defaulted to zero and then we need to set up an interpolation.
And this interpellation for our progress will be the console progress inter-relate.
You call this state DOT progress Don inter-relate and the input range will start at zero and then because
we want it to be dynamic we'll just say it's questions length and then for the output range will be
0 percent to 100 percent.
So interpolate we'll figure out based upon the number of questions that we have what percentage needs
to be applied so that it will progress appropriately across the screen when new question is answered.
And now we can set up our progress styles to say Konst progress style is equal to the width and will
pass in our progress and interpolate and take our progress style and we will pass it into our animated
view here.
Now if we look at our interpellation we'll see that the input to our progress should be the current
question that we are on.
So in our handle answer we'll need to flip this around a little bit.
We'll do a parallel so they're animated up parallel which will take an array of two questions.
And will non-call start on our animated up parallel and this one will be animated timing as well.
This state up progress and then we'll pass into value which is just me this state that index plus one
with the same duration.
So now this progress is being updated with the next current question because I'll take the next question
right here and then.
The range is dynamic based upon state.
So now when we refresh and we answer a question can see that our value will animate our progress of
our estimate as we answer questions.