When dealing with animations and physics there may be times where you want physics to be applied but
over a set period of time.
So we have a duration of 500.
However with spring for example you don't necessarily know the time that it's going to take but with
a timing animation combined with easing we know the exact physics that will happen but also the exact
duration that will happen.
These will all be very specific to your use case.
Take a look at what the default animation would be for just doing a translate Y would just move off
of the screen.
But if we add easing will use easing that back to start it'll move backwards refresh and move backwards
and then zoom forwards.
We can use bounce refresh and we can see it bounced some of this to 300 instead can move bounce to elastic
and it shot past and then came back and then we can also do arbitrary Bezier curves.
So these are all going to be very specific to your use case so read about easing the documentation will
point you to easing dot net which allows you to craft different evenings and see how they will apply
to your timed animation.