The animated spring function allows you to define an animation that operates off of friction and tension.
This is the best way to mimic and animate as if it was physical motion.
In our demo we have an animated value set up on stage that defaults to one set up an animated style
with a scale transform and we have a touchable without feedback that calls this hand-bill press function
and animates a view inside of it.
In our Hendel press function we're going to say animated got spring the enemy that last spring matches
all of the other animated functions so it will take the this the enemy the very first say this state
animation will then pass in a configuration object what we'll do is say to value of two and then call
start the enemy does bring has various defaults set up.
It has a friction of seven and a tension of 40 as its default.
So now when we refresh our simulator and we press on it we can see that it has a slight bounce to a
slight spring.
However if we want to make this more noticeable we'll change our friction and make it less friction
than 7 so we'll pass to you and then we'll say tension of a hundred and sixty.
This adds basically energy to the spring so the higher this value the more springy the spring will be.
And then this will cause it to slow down so the higher this is than the quicker that the spring will
slow down.
However with a low friction This means that it will bounce.
So if we refresh this and we press on our thing we can see that it's much Springer and bouncier than
it was before.
In our start function we're just going to call an animated timing to reset our scales so we'll see animated
timing this state animation to value of one for the duration of 100 milliseconds and then we'll call
start.
And this will allow us to see kind of when the animation settles down.
So when I press this it'll bounce for a while and then shoot back down to 1.
And that's when the animation has completed.
So you can see that that took a little bit of time and that's because it's mimicking a real spring.
And that animation does take a little bit of time to settle before it is completed.
Finally one other thing to note is that spring allows the value to overshoot.
And what that means is that even though this is saying to value of two that is only a a spot where it
will settle it will be complete when it reaches the valley of two.
So this actually will bring the past two and the value will go higher than two.
And so if we press on this we can see that it actually went higher than the point that it eventually
settled at to show this off.
We're going to attach a listener to our animation value.
So when we say this state animation and Lisner which will receive a callback which perceives a object
with a value key on it I will say cancel the log or value inside of here we're going to say press command
d or.
Or if you are on a different development environment we're going to bring up the development menu and
say debug G-S remotely.
This will open up a debugger here and press command shift I or however you open up your console and
we will switch back to our simulator when we press when we refresh and then press on arsh bring value.
We can see that it takes a little while to settle down again and that there are a significant amount
of values especially here that shot over the value that we were going towards.