Animated the event is a helper function that will take a configuration and traverse that configuration
and then call set value on the animated values that you've passed to it.
This is typically used with a scroll of view pan responder and anything else where you just need a function
returned and the configuration to traverse the arguments that are called and automatically call set
value on your enemy to add value to demonstrate this were going to cause this background to change whenever
things are scrolled.
So we have an animated value here on State interpretating from orange to blue over 3000.
And that is coming from our style's dark content the styles that content is just some fit content with
a 3000 pixel height set on it.
So on our scroll view we're going to say scroll event throttle is equal to 16.
And this is saying we want our onscreen function to be called every 16 milliseconds.
And that'll help us achieve 60 frames per second.
Now we can define our on scroll function.
And typically you would have to do a function here or something else which is then called with an event.
We then need to get the native event content offset Y and then we would say this that state that animation
that set value this value.
This is a little bit robust and so we can add the enemy event helper because we are grabbing the first
argument of this function.
That means that we need to say animated event.
We then pass in an array and whichever index of the array that you put your configuration object is
going to be the map to the argument order that is called.
So because for the first argument we just want this first index put an object here and say a native
event within say content set Y and then this state animation and then we This will then traverse the
first event argument that gets called and then automatically call the set value on this that state information.
And now that we have this set up for the refresh.
This means that as we scroll our enemy values getting set which then this interpolation is being affected
and our colors are changing.