Animated K allows you to apply a velocity and a deceleration to an intermediate value.
This is typically going to be used whenever you need to have a throw flick or some sort of gesture animation
that the user has released and then mission needs to continue.
But look realistic.
So we will have an animated value x y because we will be controlling the x and y direction of this particular
square here.
We will need to create a pan responder.
So we'll see this dot and this core pan responder is equal to a pan responder create.
And there are various methods to tell this Panne responder what to do.
And the first one will be on START should set pan responder and that will just be a function that returns
true.
And this will just say if this pan responder's hit that the view is touched we should start the pan
responder touch events and then the other is going to be on move.
Should set pan responder and this is just going to say if we continue to move should be keep calling
our on pand response Buddh function and we say yes.
So in order to capture the value of the finger the press and the drag.
We're going to need to use the on plan responder move callback which will pass an animated event which
takes an array.
And in our case the enemy the unpin respond or move is called with two arguments.
The first is the event and the second is going to be the gesture.
And that is just going to be a bunch of information about the gesture that is happening from the user.
So what we actually care about is the gesture states that will say no for this first argument and then
we'll say object with a DX and pass that to this state to animation X and then r Delta Y and say this
state animation y.
So these are both going to be capturing the delta of the the gesture.
So if I press here and I move in this direction there's a change from the original point which was here
to here on both the X and the y axis C is and that is going to be captured and automatically set on
our animation value.
Now where the decay comes in is when we release or the user releases the the box that it's throwing.
And it will have a particular velocity that we will get from the gesture state.
So we'll say on Pan responder release and it will be called with an event and then a velocity the X
which is the velocity x and a v y
with those values will then call animated to K and pass and R this state animation will then say velocity
and pass in an x velocity which is just going to be v x and r y velocity which will be Y and then we'll
say deceleration.
And it just defaults to 0.9 7 and then we will call start on our enemy to decay.
Now that are pan responder is created.
We need to apply our panhandlers to the view that we want our gestures to work on.
And so in that case when it's a dot dot dot which is a spread operator to say this dot pan responder
pan handlers.
And this will apply these specific props to this view so that our gesture handlers will be culled accordingly.
One other thing to note is that we are using the animated value that x y get translate transform this
will automatically decompose our enemy and animated values on the x and y into a translate X and a translate
y.
So now if we go ahead and refresh this we can drag this around.
And then as we release it you can see that we throw it and it will then slowly decelerate.
However there's one thing that if you slightly move it here and then press on it here you can see that
there is a jump.
And this is because of the Delta that is being set the delta the animated value already has a value.
And then we're setting a Delta value on top of it which would then be jump back to zero.
So it will then cause this to jump.
In order to make this smooth we need to use the set offset from animated on an intermediate value.
And so we need to keep track of the animated values so we're going to do that first by saying this dot
X equals zero and this y equals zero.
And then we're going to attach a listener to it soon and say this state DOT animation and listener and
that will be called with some sort of value object.
And on that value object will say this dot the square x is equal to a value of x and this underscore
Y Z equal to value Y.
And then inside of another function called on Pan responder grant
we're going to say this Stut state that animation set offset.
And we can just pass an X and say this X Y and say this.
Y.
And this will then set the offset of our animation.
And then at the same time we need to then reset our.
Our animation intermediate values back to zero.
So this offset will then apply our current values to the animated values so that the Delta will take
effect correctly.
So say this state animation that set value x of 0 and y zero so now that that's working we can refreshed
this and move our box and then press it again and move it again.
And that is working because when we drag it we're setting a specific delta position which is just an
offset from where this box was originally in the middle.
And then because we're keeping track of it appear unpin responded Grant.
Nothing has happened yet.
Nothing no movements have happened yet.
We adjust the offset of this animation which is just extra values that are added to the normal value.
So this will set it to its current location as the offset.
At the same time we'll then set the to value to zero.
And that way the offset plus zero.
Basically be the same exact value.
And then as this kicks in.
It will then apply the delta from its current position plus the offset and allow us to drag it around.
And then additionally throw it if we want let's simplify this code a little bit.
It's very annoying that we have to attach a listener just to keep track of the value.
And then also send it to the offset just to clear the animated value to zero before we simplify this.
Let's take a look at what is exactly happening.
We are setting the offset of the previous value and then resetting our animated value to zero.
That was because we were updating with the delta x and Delta Y and that way the offset is now going
to be the previous Delta.
So whenever we move this it will be in that exact location.
So what we can then do instead of tracking and doing all this we can just call the extract offset function
and that way we don't have to keep track of any of our values either.
This will do exactly what we were already doing.
It'll take the current value that we have here move it into the offset and then update the value to
zero.