That ad is a helper method that allows you to take an animated value and synchronously add an additional
animated value or a normal value to it.
This is going to help with libraries and other things that require you to pass in values and synchronously
add them rather than using offsets potentially.
And then additionally you can nest these as much as you want.
So you could create sort of mathematical formulas for your animated values if you needed to do some
sort of math based animation.
So we're just going to take a look at the basic case.
So here we are going to say Kautz new animation is equal to animated ad and the first argument is going
to be this does state animation because that's what our enemy of the value is.
And then we're just going to pass in a random value.
We're going to say 50.
However we're just going to sign this here so we say Konst random values equal to 50 past that are in
value and now we can see that if we removed this and switched this out to be new animation when we save
see it shifted down 50.
This will also work with other animated values so we can instead of saying 50 here will say new animated
value.
And when I save this this will refresh and nothing will have happened.
And our animations will still work as normal and this will receive that 50 offset.