Animated timing is a nother math function that allows us to nest as much as we want and create formulas
if we desired.
However we're just going to show how to use it rather quickly and we'll say conc random value equals
six and then we will create our new animation and use our animated multiply pass and this state animation
and then our random value.
Now we'll go replace or this animation with our new animation and we save this we see that nothing happened
because 6 is multiplying by default which is zero.
However whenever we animate this when we press on it it'll multiply by this value that we've given it
times.
Each of these steps as it's animating from 0 to 50.
So that means that we'll go to 300 rather than just the 50.
So we can say we will press on this and watch it go to 300 and then it will snap back.
And then once again we can replace this with new animated value.
Save that and the same effect will happen.