Animated modules that allows you to do modulo arithmetic and get the remainder after division essentially
you do the division of the two values take the result multiplied by the divisor which is the bottom
number.
Then take the dividend which is a top to him and said tracked out that resulting number the value is
the modulo.
Now one of the main uses for this is clock arithmetic.
However we'll just do some spinning in our demo so we'll first set up a random value which will assign
to three and then will say it's new animation is equal to animated modulo.
So this state animation and our random value.
And then we'll do an interpellation on this and say Konst interpolated Ziegel to a new animation button
Triple-A input range from zero to three in our output range will be 0 degrees to 270 degrees.
And then we will pass this in as a rotate transform.
And now as this animates it will be continually divided and we'll take the remainder interpret it and
then we'll figure out a rotation so we can do that and see that it spins.