Sometimes when using animated We want an animation to take immediate effect.
However it's inside of an interpolation and not necessarily capable of using set value in order to do
this.
We use a point ninety nine cliff but we have set up here is a box that will drag when it stays on this
site.
It will stay a particular color and when it goes to this side it will turn red and flip over first thing
we need to do.
Set up an animated value x y that we can store our drag position in.
So we set up some animation onstage an animated value X-Y And now we need to set up our pan responder
and we can do that in component will mount.
So just sign this dot underscore Panne responder and I have a helper Sculpin create this will initialize
a responder.
And here because we want to preserve our drag location we'll say this state animation but extract offset
that way to move our delta on our animated value into our offset so that next time it will repair or
move to store the new Delta we will need to do anything under these so we can move that and then we'll
use animated events and we will pass and no because we don't need anything off the event.
We just need stuff off of our state which is a second pass DX into this state animation X and our D-y
into this state animation.
Why now that we have our panel responder already for movement we can go ahead and first spread our panhandlers
on to our enemy to view.
So we'll see what the spread this Duckpin responder and pan handlers.
Not just because you spread the sand does not mean that we're ready to actually drag it.
We need to do it translate translate translate translate wise with say Konst animated styles or transform
and the animated x value x y has a helper function so we'll say dot dot state animation done get translate
transform.
This would turn a two objects inside of an array.
So we spread them into a new array because we'll apply some other transform player and I just have to
translate X and translate y for us.
And now that we have our animated styles already we can apply them to our animated view.
And if we refresh we can drag our box around.
Now as we drag this box around we have half of the height here in half the height here.
So we're going to get the height of the window with our dimensions get
and that way we can craft an input range that will be able to calculate the exact spot that we need
to do our point ninety nine cliff and because our input range will be used for both the background and
the scale interpellation we can just say Konst input range and get array here.
And the idea behind the point anyway cliff is that you define a value which is our start and then define
a second value right before the other value needs to take effect.
So in our case that's going to be the height divided by two minus 50 point zero one and the fifty point
zero one comes from this box being 50 by 50 and then we'll finish this off a high divided by two minus
50.
That way this sits at a point nine nine and then immediately toggles over to the next level.
So if this was say two hundred and fifty this would sit at one ninety nine point nine nine and then
this would then say we need to kick off a new input range at 200.
Well then finishes off with height.
So now that we have our input range set up we can actually craft our interpretations so essay contest
background color inter-relate and we'll trigger that off of that state animation.
Why inter-relate will pass in our input range here.
And then the other key part of the point ninety nine cliff is having an output range that is either
is the same here if you want the animation is to be the same or just defining something that will immediately
take effect on the other side.
In our case we want to have the same color when it's from 0 which is up here to half the height which
is right here.
And then as soon as it hits this cliff it will flip over to a pure red color.
So now we can take this background color and interpolate and pass it into our animated styles.
So if we refresh back here we now have a blue purple box that you can drag and as we drag as soon as
we hit our point any cliff we can see that it turns red immediately.
There is no animation that takes effect.
It flips to red.
Now we'll add one more interpellation will do a flip interplay so say conc flip and interpolate.
So you could do this state animation.
Why and interpolate passenger input range and then our output range will be one and one because this
will go into scale and we want it to flip and then negative one negative one which will flip it over
a reflection point.
So pass that in here to our transform.
A scale here with our Phlip interpret and if we refresh grab our box and drag as soon as we hit this
line you'll see that our box turns red and flips over.
Now if we don't have an immediate point nine nine cliff.
So for example if we were to rather than have in minus 50 here and just have a point 199 roughly point
ninety nine to two hundred and fifty if those were the actual numbers then a gradual animation will
happen.
And that's not what we want.
So if we refresh this this will now be fifty point zero or 1.
So there's a point there and unclear but there's not an immediate point zero one more.
On the other side and this will then actually cause an interpellation to happen.
So as we get closer and closer you can see that as soon as you get within 50 years the box touches it
will shrink down and then grow on the other side.
But once we add back our cliff our animations will take immediate effects.