Animated doesn't support unmounting animations.
However using state and the start callback we can craft something that does and on Mount.
So the first thing we need to do is set up some state.
So we'll say animation and get a new animated value and we'll pass in one as our default we'll just
animate to zero as we're unmounting.
And then we will also say visible true.
This will allow us to toggle whether or not we have the box mounted or not.
And now that we have our animation set up we'll start our animation this animation is called when we
press on our box so it was intimated that timing pass in that state that animation will go to value
of zero with the duration of 1400 milliseconds.
This is quite long however we're just giving ourselves time to be able to press on it to interrupt our
animation.
And now before we call star on our animation let's set up our animated styles.
The first will be our interpellation for translate Why so say conc translate why interpolate.
If you go to state that animation inter-relate and then we'll say input range of 0 to 1 with an output
range of 500 to 0.
And you can see that this maps to what we have here so one to zero.
This won't go anywhere.
And as you animate towards zero we will move towards 500 and this will animate down.
And then we can pass that into context animated styles.
And we will also do an opacity so Pasotti this state animation that all happens correctly because it'll
go from one to zero.
And then there are transform
translate y translate Y and interpolate and move past this into our box.
So now that we have our styles all set up we can now trigger our animation.
We'll just call Start here and see what happens so we press it and we animate down and away.
However this is still around.
If we were animate back to one this would slide up from the bottom.
So let's see what we can do about unmounting it.
What we call START.
It takes a callback which passes in an object as the first argument and that argument has or that object
has a finished flag on it.
Now finished is going to tell us whether or not this animation was completed and uninterrupted and when
I say uninterrupted I mean that another animation was not triggered on this outstate animation.
So if we do a console log of finished and we can go do a de-bug of our G-S remotely and when we press
on this our debugger will open and if we press on this you can see that we got a true for our finished
value.
However when refresh and we press on it again we can see that false was called and then true because
we were calling the same exact function star animation.
So this was running.
We then pressed on it again and this attempted to animate the same exact value.
Granted it's still going to zero.
So then our start callback was called for our first animation and then the second animation kicked in
and continued the animation.
And called Finished of true because the second animation did completely finished without us interrupting
it.
So there are a few ways that we can handle this generally speaking we would probably want to trigger
we would want to deviate what function is being called or or what animation is being triggered here
whether or not this was running or not.
We'll take a slightly lazier route just to a set time out.
Of 0 but this will do is when we trigger our first animation and then click on our box again.
This will run however it will run synchronously.
And then this other second animation will kick in.
So this will just say set up our animation stuff to trigger on the next tick.
And so technically we'll be animating to zero will be interrupted.
It will start animating to zero again and then this set time will tick over and then we will start doing
our own animation.
So this is less than ideal but its going to make us it easier to understand what's exactly happening.
So now that we have our set time out let's refresh this and we'll do and if finished else so if we have
success it successfully finished then we can do this set state and we'll toggle our visible to false.
That means that our animation has completed and are we're able to then unmount our box.
However it hasn't completed that we'll just animate our box with a spring animation so we'll do this
state animation to value of one and call star on that.
So this gives us the ability to decide whether or not we unmount when we're done or otherwise we need
to reset our animated value back to its default so that this whole flow can get triggered again.
So refresh this and we test it out.
This completed.
Now if we did we interrupt it we see that springs back.
Now the only thing left to do is toggle are mounted with our visible state.
So we will just go on here to our touch without feedback and say this to stay visible and Anne and wrap
this.
So we start out being visible so this will render and then as soon as we toggle are visible to false
then it will unmount give that a shot you can see that we can spring it back and then we let it complete
and then it doesn't mount's So using this can be a great way for things like modals or something if
you have an API for a reusable component and you want to use animated to control your unmounting animations
you animate a way and then do a callback to someone up above and then they can control the unmounting
for you.