I'm not going to do any programming in this video but I'm going to show off a pointer events technique.
So we have an animated value a toggle.
True or false.
And then a press on the component instance.
Let's look at what happens when we execute our toggle.
We have a touchable without feedback.
With an animated view inside that is an interpellation.
And we just go from a tomato color to a purple ish blue color.
And we have a view here with style sheets absolute fill and it's covering this entire square here.
Now when we are true in the toggle which we have defaulted to true then this covering view sets pointier
events to none.
Meaning it will not be able to accept any touches when it's false.
We set it to auto meaning it should accept touches when pressed.
What that means is that even though it's invisible the stiles that covers just a background color of
transparent that it will receive touches.
Meaning because it's it's rendered after our button here that it will take up all the touches and nothing
can be touched.
However when this is none it says ignore all the touches on this.
So this allows us to render items next to other items that are covering the same exact space but control
which one is being touched.
This applies to animations because you can use an opacity on a particular view.
That is absolutely positioned and covering another view.
And then once the animation is complete we can toggle whether or not presses happen on which on the
covering view.
So let's take a look at what this effect is like.
So we have our toggle here when we press this it will animate.
You press this we will disable things.
So on our handle press we just simply animate to evaluate 0 0 or 1 depending on whether or not we pressed
it last.
And so let's refresh and press on this.
So at the moment toggle is true and pointer events are none.
So we can process as much as we want and kind of animate back and forth and then as soon as we toggle
our pointer event so toggle is false we can no longer press on anything to trigger our animation.
I will say that this is effectively rendering and rendering.
And when you have a lot of unnecessary views in your render that re-act native has to handle that performance
could potentially be effective.
This is just a slightly easier method to maintain views without having to do a lot of toggling of mounting
and unmounting of those animated views.