Let's start by going through the animated implementation Let's start with the outermost API.
The animated view that text image and scroll view as you can see here we import animated implementation.
We import our series of views text and image and then we will then call create animated component on
each of those and then export our animated object.
So now that you can see everything goes through create animated component.
Let's go take a look at what create animated component does.
Here we have create animated component.
You can see that it is a function that takes a component and then returns a new component.
The component has a lot on it.
In our constructor we can have b c we have a set component ref.
So we know we'll be accessing the rest of the component that we pass in if we take a look at component
will mount we see that it calls attach props.
When we when we mount we can see that we attach native events and do some things when we have a native
animation.
And then additionally when we unmount we can see we detach and remove any sort of negative events.
The key here is actually in the attach props that happens in our component will mount.
So let's take a look at attach props and see that we first define a callback and that callback will
access this component which is set from the ref and see if it has a set of props.
If it does then we will execute a particular flow.
However if it does not then we will trigger a force update.
So in this callback is called We can see that we get a component called serenader props.
And then with our props animated that we're about to create.
We will then say get the animated value for it.
Now this props animated is a new animated props that receives the current props for the next props as
well as the callback we created here.
We also have saved off the old props animated here.
And then called detach on it so that way we don't have any memory leaks.
I can put a wall mount called attach props and then also what we'll do is call attach props with our
component will receive props and then in our render the props to animated that we have set up we will
then spread in as our props rather than spreading in this type props.
We have this interface that we then spread our props and we also get our breath.
Here you can see and then some explanation about why or why or why we don't use collapsable for needed
use.
And then also set component ref and then also get know that we can be called when we need to get access
to the internal ref of our component to do measurers or anything like that.
Now all of this is driven based upon animated props and some call back that is passed to it and then
called that then calls suddenly to prop's on it.
So let's take a look at animated props animated props has a constructor here that takes some props.
If we have props style which if we had a style object then we would create a new animated style and
pass in our Propst style.
And then at some point whenever we need to get access to it we have a value call.
So back in our animated implementation with that create animated component we can see that in our callback
all we're doing is calling get animated value for our call it is set native props whoever in our render
recalling get value.
The reason why this is is that if an animation is happening we need to call get value because of a set
state then happens.
We need all of the props to pass over.
Otherwise they would be blown away because they'll be all updated on the native side.
However when we're just calling set native props all we need to do is send over the values that we want
to change.
So those are just the animated values that are actually changing.
So back in our animated implementation for our animated props we see we just loop over.
This is for all of them and if they are animated values or if they're an enemy event then we do special
things by calling value on that animated value.
Otherwise we just rebuild our props with key and value.
And then for the animated value we only look for instance of animated and get our animated value for
just the particular props that are animated that need to change at that particular time.
Now there's a lot of calls to attach and detach.
And let's take a look at what happens when we say set value on a normal animated value without going
through animated timing or animated spring feel like here this is set value and this is on an animated
value.
So this would be animated value that we usually use when set value is called we stop any animations
that are happening and call update value with the value that we've passed in.
So now let's go look at Update value of value.
Then we'll take the value assigned to the animated value and then flush the value.
But flush does is find the animated styles and then eventually we will call update on the animated style.
Now we are calling update.
And let's go back and look at our animated implementation and we can see that we have an update here
on our animated props that we have initiated.
So this is the animated props that we passed in from our create animated component right here.
So that's the callback passed into our animated props are animated props just got up called.
We call this callback that we have saved off and now this execute which says hey by the way an animated
value has been updated.
So now we have our callback.
If we have set native props which we do we will then call this some components that need props with
all of the animated values in case they've all changed.
So now we're just sending the new animated values over so that in a nutshell is how it works we create
a new enemy the component that sits in between and intercepts all of the props.
And any time we pass in an animated value that changes then a callback is triggered and set native props
will then send all the new values over.
However any time that state happens we just get all the new values and spread them on and we continue
on like we're using just props.
Even though we have sat in between and interfered and adjusted all the values with the animated values.