Create an admitted component allows us to build and construct an animated version of any particular
component.
In our case we're going to use the native button and we're going to turn it into an animated button
so say conc animated button is equal to animated create animated component will pass in our button.
And now you can use animated button as if it were a button and any of the values that we place on it
can be animated.
So we can still press this even though it's an animated button and not our normal button.
Typically when we animate we're animating styles however animated also works on props with the button
the color of the text is controlled by the color prop so we can say color is equal to our animated value.
So we need to set up our animated value interpellation for the colors say conc animated color Zegers
with this state animation inter-relate input range will be 0 to 1 in our output range will be these
two colors and then we'll pass and our animated color interpretation snow and we save this because this
is Orange and it is starting at 0 as a default value.
We can see that our button now has changed to orange.
And that process or animation will kick off and we'll see it transition to blue and then our Once finished
all transition back to zero
a word of warning if the component that you have passed into the animated component does not have a
set native prop's call a force update will be called to force all the subtree to render.
So what some libraries will do to be compatible with animated is they'll get a reference to a node for
example if we got a ref here
and then we would on our class if we were to pass this particular component into an animated value.
It's a set native props take our props here.
And then call this button set native props props this would only be if we were to say pass and if this
was a reusable component and this was our magical button and we were passing it into there that would
then be detected by animated and we would forward it along our set native props to the real actual reference
that we were the real actual native component.