Set props is how animated works.
So let's go take a look at how we can use set native props.
One thing many people attempt to do is disable a scroll view.
However sometimes there's a significant amount of content and calling a state may cause performance
issues.
So let's take a look at how we can use set of props to bypass set state.
Now we start by setting and enabled true on our component instance.
And that's because our scroll view here is always going to have scroll enabled defaulted to true.
The key here is that we need to get this scroll which is our reference to our this particular component
instance otherwise we won't be able to call setting of props.
So now up in our handle toggle we can just do a scroll native prop's
and we need to pass in an object and then scroll and enabled this dot enabled.
We don't need to pass back all of the props that are being passed into the scroll you just the ones
that we want to change.
Now we're always just setting this to you so let's just talk let's say this dot enabled equals not the
start enabled.
So that way if it's true it would target the false and if it's false it will be targeted to true.
So now if we go out and we refresh this and see that when we're scrolling in the background will change.
However we toggle and we can no longer scroll toggle back.
And now we're back to being able to scroll.
This also works with styles.
Do you know that the style is a single prop so passing over a new style with set props.
We'll blow all the sow's away so make sure you send over the ones that you are currently applied to
the scroll of you not just the ones that you want to change.
So let's set up a styles would say style equals an array and styles that scroll.
And if we're not unable then we'll say style push styles that hide outs will just say style push styles
that show and then we can pass in our style here to our set native props.
So this is just going to tile an array of styles that we're sending over and if we look here our height
and show are just setting opacity of either 0 or 1.
So now if we refresh this and scroll be disabled as well as toggling the opacity so we toggle and we
can take it back.
I don't recommend using Set native props as in lieu of using set state but sometimes you need to bypass
state and the defense and the overhead that comes with updating all of the views.
So use it but use it sparingly.