D-3 is a very popular SVGA library.
However I also had a lot of interpellation helpers inside of it.
These were packaged up in a separate NPM module called D-3 internally.
We're going to take a look at how we can use D-3 inter-relate and animated to recreate an effect that
we would typically use with just animated.
So we take a look at our render function.
We all have a background color and a transform for a translate y to refresh this and we animate and
see that we offset 200 animate from a tomato to a blue.
So let's copy and paste these so we have access to them later and we can delete all re-animated styles
and also change this from a regular animated view to view.
And then we can also move this because we're just going in passing in a single style of box.
I'll make sure we get a ref of the views we can call scintillated frumps when we press on our button
we call our handle press and it will trigger an animation from 0 to 1.
So why don't we attach a state animation.
Add listener so we can get access to the value that animated is animating will then set up to interpolations
will say
Kant's position and interpolate and will use just interpolate number from D-3 in chirpily so was plate
number and we'll say from 0 to 200.
This is basically the equivalent of an input range in animated within say contest color.
Interpret is able to interpolate or G-B will pass in our to our G.V. colors.
These will return functions that will take a value between 0 and 1 and return the appropriate interpolated
value for us.
So this is why we have a animated value from 0 to 1.
So we can now set up a contest position and say position interpret and pass in or value and then also
do it can't see color and do our color interplay and pass in our value.
So these are calling our interpreters passing in a value that is between 0 and 1.
And then this over turn the interpolated values that we can use.
So now we just need to rebuild our style so that we can override it with native props.
So we say Konst style is equal to an array because we already have a style box on here so we don't want
to blow away the box styling styles top box and also a new object and we'll say background color all
passenger color and we'll set up a transform
past and or translate Y and pasan our position.
So now we can then do our view and call set native props pass in our new style for a style object.
So in refresh this and we press on our box we have the same exact effect.
We just rebuilt it using D-3 interpolate and set native props.