Animated does not support animating SVGA paths.
However D-3 inter-relate does but D-3 interpolate depends on the Dom to parse out the D-3 path.
However there is a D-3 inter-relate path that uses just the strings to figure that out.
So we'll install D-3 inter-relate path and import inter-relate path to either ensure path does not handle
very complex paths unfortunately.
So we'll just keep it simple by animating a simple circle to a larger circle.
Also use reacting as Fiji because it follows the standards of the web.
So let's take a look at our under function.
We have a touchable without feedback to trigger a press.
We have a SVGA with the width and height of 150 and then we have a path and also we get a ref to that
path so we can call set native props in our handle press.
We have an animated sequence which will start by animating our default value of 0 to 1.
Will then delay for 200 milliseconds and then will animate back to zero.
So let's set up in our component amount and interpellation.
So say Konst path and interpolate is equal to interpolate path that we've imported from the D-3 inter-relate
path and will pass in our start path and our path will then attach our listeners state to animation.
Add listner which we call with our value and then will have our function and then we'll say Konst path
is equal to path inter-relate value.
It doesn't matter that we are estimating from 0 to 1 and then back to zero.
This listener will always be called with the value that we are.
That is the animated value and this interplay path will always take that value and figure out the appropriate
path to give us.
So now we can do this path which is our component called Set native props and will update the D prop
and will pass in our new path.
Now if we go refresh this we can trigger press on our SPG and see that it expanded to a larger circle.
Delayed and then animated backdown.