Reacting of ships with re-acting of art bindings However you need to install the art library to take
advantage of it.
The only issue with Art is it does not conform to the web standards like reacting to Fiji.
So I still use re-active as.
However we use some of the helper methods from the art library that we installed some of the power of
art comes from being able to target both canvas as Fiji via all with the same exact API.
It comes with helpers like tweeting that helps you morph SVGA pads from one to the other.
So we're going to take advantage of the CEG path and the tween function from the art library.
So we have our start path which is a arrow and our end path which is a checkmark.
So we also have a similar animation and a path rendering our start path.
So again we need to create a path interpolator.
So say Konst path and interpolate and we'll say tween.
And that takes the start path and the path tween from Art can handle significantly more complex paths
than D-3 interpolate path.
The next thing we need to do is set up a empty path so say Konst P is equal to a new SPG path.
Then once again we'll set up our listeners say state animations add listener take a function and give
us our value and then our path internally has a tween function on it and that will receive the value
between 0 and 1 so say path and interpolate tween pasand our value.
And then it also has a the ability to apply to an arbitrary path and so was a path.
Interpolate apply to path and paths in our path.
So this does a lot of mutations rather than being a pure function.
So then we just need to call our set of props so we say this stop path set need of props and just D
and our path will be to SVGA so it will return a SPG path that we can use.
So now one we're refreshed this and we trigger our animation we can watch it transform to a check mark
and then transform back to an arrow.