Flubber is an amazing SVGA path.
Interpolator that aims to have smoother animations in between.
Let's take a look at how we can use flubber to animate as CGI pads on Riak native.
We have a short path which is a star and we're going to transform it in an animated fashion to a heart.
So the first thing we're going to do in our component amount is set up a path and so say Cotts path
interpret is equal to interpret which is from the level of a library.
It'll take a start path and path and then we'll configure it with maxed segment length of one the lower
the number here will produce a smoother animation.
However at the sacrifice of performance but we'll just keep it at one and you can play with it.
If your animations are not being performant now that we have our interpreter you can set up our listener
so is state animation listener.
Get our value creator function and then say Konst path is equal to path and interpolate with our value.
And we set this up path that native props and we'll update our D with our new path.
And now when we refresh our emulator and we kick off our animation you can see that will transform into
a heart and then transform back into a star.