A lot of the power inside of the animated library comes from interpellation you're able to do interpellation
on interpolations and it will still be reactive regardless of a timing or anything else that is triggering
the animation.
So let's go down to render function and set up our first interpellation say Konst animated and interpolate
is equal to this state to animation which is our animated value and call and interpolate which takes
an object and takes an input range and an output range the input range will be looks at the animated
value and then determines how it should be interpreted to the output range the input range must also
always be increasing.
So when we say input range we can do to 1 0 we would have to do 0 1 to interplay input range is not
necessary to start at zero it could start at any numbers we could say negative 1 but it is always must
be increasing.
Now we'll define our output range output range can be anything and can.
Doesn't have to be in an increasing fashion.
So in our case we say zero because at the zero mark we don't want anything happening that at the one
mark of our animation will say 300 and then we'll bring it back down to zero once we hit to.
So now that we have an interpellation Let's go ahead and set up some animated styles.
So I say Konst animated styles sequel to transform here.
And we'll pass this into to translate Y and pass and animated and interpolate.
And now that we have our styles we can take this and place it on our box and Zaal and refresh here and
we trigger our animation by pressing on this animation our animation will run and it will then go to
from 0 to 1.
And once that is complete then it will quickly go to two which will kind of reset back to zero.
So one thing to note is that when we do an interpellation it returns a new animated value.
What that means is we can interpret off of our interpellation.
So we'll say Konst interpolated interpolate and we'll set up an interpolation to control our capacity.
So as say animated interpolate to interpret and we're no longer operating off of the 0 1 2 range.
We're actually operating off of the zero 300 0 so the output range of an interpret will become the input
range of another inter-relate.
So that means our input range will be 0 to 300 and our output range will be one to point five.
So this will map to an opacity and this will basically as this moves towards 300 This will move towards
from one point five.
And then this as it moves from 300 back to zero this will basically move from point five back to 1.
Now let's apply our interpellation to our capacity so we'll say opacity patient are interpreted interpreted
and now want to refresh this we can see as it moves towards 300 it hits the point five of Pasotti and
then it goes back to one opacity.
Now let's do one more interpellation we could technically interpret all of this and interpolate but
we'll continue and off of our animated interpolate up above.
So I say Konst translate X interpret Zucco to animated inter-family interpret and that will take an
input range and an output range and the range will be something crazy like input range 0 30 50 80 100
150 200 Nine-Nine and 300.
It doesn't matter how many values are in your output range.
You must just have the same amount of values in the output range.
And so for output range it doesn't even matter what the values are here either.
So we would say 0 and do the exact opposite.
Negative 30 negative 50 jump all the way back to 80 back to negative would go to 300 and then 0 and
then negative 100.
So these are close together so in a very quick span of time it will drop from zero to negative 100.
So now we can take this and put it into a new transform translate X and refresh this.
And so when we press on this all at the same time we will go from zero to 300.
Translate why our Passey will go from 1 to point five and back to 1 and then we will do this crazy sequence
of events.