With animated animated values are just numbers.
However in order to do colors we must use interpellation.
So now let's go down to a render function and set up and interpolate space say conc color and interpolate
to this state animation that interpolate which would take an input Prange and will say 0 1 and 2.
That way we can define a three step color when interpolating colors.
They must be in R G B our G.P.A. or in HCO.
So we're going to paste in an output range here and we'll have three colors that go from green to blue
to red or red to blue I should say.
So now we can set up cots animated styles which passes into a background color and give it our color
internally and then we'll pass this into our box.
And because we never specified a value down here there was no value of color for our box now because
we did default 2.0 our interpellation will say zero maps to this green color.
Now if we press on our box because we have a press to trigger an animation we'll go from zero to 2 and
watch it step through changing colors regardless of what color it is.
It'll figure out how to interpret it to it.
Let's set up one more interpellation.
We don't we aren't able to interpolate off of inter-relations that output colors because the output
of this is not another number to interpolate to.
So unlike numbers we can't do that.
So we'd have to say Konst background style is equal to background color and we'll just do an inline
interpellation here and say this state animation interpolate
Well then define an input range of zero to two and then an output range of the same exact color.
So they're both a red color.
However all we're changing is the alpha channel value.
So interpolate will interpolate and animate just the opacity of this particular color.
Let's apply our background style to our container and watch it take effect.
So when refresh we can see that we have this tomato color and animates from 0 to 2.
All that will change is the alpha value.