Even though a rotation is just a number an enemy that values support that we still need to use interpellation
to define our rotation.
So let's first set up a rotation so say Konst X inter-relate to this state to animation that interpolate
our input range is just 0 to 1 and her output range will be zero degrees to 360 degrees.
Now we'll set up our animated styles so say conc animated styles siecle to transform passen rotate and
fastener X inter-relate.
Well then take this and apply it to our box
so now refresh this we can see this.
When I press on it will do a full 360 degree rotation.
However we can do a singular rotate or we can operate on the x and y independently.
So if we were to take this rotate and switch it over to just a rotate X and we refreshed this and re
trigger animations we'll see a flip over the y axis.
Additionally if you prefer radians as opposed to degrees the enemy of the library also supports radians.
If we were to reverse this we'd have the same exact animation because six point two at 3 1 9 radians
is the equivalent of 360 degrees.
So let's convert this back.
I will set up a y interpellation for rotate y.
So say Cotts Why interpret is equal to this state animation internally.
So input range is zero point five and one will then specifier output range as 0 degrees 0 degrees and
then 180 degrees.
So this will basically wait for our animation to be halfway completed without doing a rotation on the
Y on the Y rotate before it then triggers a 180 degrees on the Y rotate.
So we then define our rotate y I'm passing a y interpret We then refresh once we trigger this animation
we'll go halfway before it does a rotate y.