Interpolations take more than just input range and output range.
They also take an extrapolate value this extrapolate value defaults to extend which just says it's going
to extend the range beyond whatever the output range is.
So let's take a look at a quick example of this.
We have our animation that goes to.
And then once it's completed it will animate to one back to its beginning.
And because we have to find the input range from one to two and our output range from one to two these
will this map linearly to the values.
So if we refresh this and press on it as we animated to will animate to the two times the scale and
then back down to one with this animation here.
So let's take a look if we comment out this two and switch it to two values of three.
Now our input range does not go to three.
And so what will happen is it will analyze this step range between 1 and 2 to the output range of 1
and 2 and then figure out what this third value will be.
So now if we refreshed this and press on it rather than animating to to animate to three times a scale
this can be something that is beneficial.
However there are times where you want a separate thing to happen.
So for example there's extrapolate clamp extrapolate clamp will take a look at the output range and
once the input range is beyond it on either the left or right side whatever this is at it will not be
onto or go be on one.
So now if we refresh even though we're animating to 3 would be over here and with the default of extend
it would figure out that we need to go to a a scale of three.
It will stop at two
the other extrapolation value is identity what identity will do is once the input range has exceeded
rather than clamping like we have here it will just assume the value of the animated value.
So let's switch it over to identity and rather than animating 2 to 1 to 2 for output range we'll do
one 1.1.
So once your input range and our estimate of value is exceeded at the 2.
It will immediately skip to a scale of 2 and then animate to 3 and we can see that by refreshing here
slowly to one point one hits two and continues to three.
However when this animates backwards to 1 from 3 Once it is then within the two range.
Now our IMPA range in our output range in our interpellation will kick in and we can see it do it step
backwards as well.
Let's switch back to how we can see that we also have extrapolate left and extrapolate right.
So you can define how something should happen on the left and the right.
So let's switch this and put an extrapolate left with a clamp and we'll add instead of a two value of
one.
What added to a value of zero.
However we're still animating to a value of three to begin.
And because we are not defining and extrapolate right of clamp this will then continue on to three.
And once it tries to animate back down to zero which would then continue this along and animate this
value this box to disappear.
It will stop at one.
So we can see that we press this enemy to three sheets back down to one but our animated values actually
down at zero.
And that's because you've defined and extrapolate left side.
So over here of clamp.