It common pattern on mobile is a shared element and what is shared elmet means is we have one particular
view with an image and when we do some sort of action that element will transition and appear as if
it's in the other view as well.
Reac native doesn't support reparenting or anything like that.
So we have to simulate exactly what's happening.
I'll go into the actual technical details in Tauriel.
However let's analyze this animation from a non re-act standpoint.
First we have a photo grid and when we select a photo let's focus on the photo to start you can see
that this actual photo seemingly grows to meet some sort of dimensions appear so free press on it.
You can see that it will expand and grow and that there is a white background like like it has basically
pulled right up from inside this scroll scrollable container to the top of the screen.
Then let's focus on the text.
So when we open this there is the bottom text and it seems like it fades in and slides up and back.
So if we select this and if we close this we can watch it so it fades and slides down and then fades
in and slides up and there seems to be a slight spring up here as well.
You see little bounce when analyzing these kind of animations.
There may be some significant steps to kind of translate that to a re-act native or re-act slash animated
concept.
So we do have to pull apart exactly what's happening and then recreate that interaction using what sort
of mechanisms that we have and that's animated that set state.
And that's series of other sort of tech techniques that we've talked about to kind of pull this off.