I'm going to show you a technique to do shared element transition using with height and absolute positioning.
If you take a look at some of the other shared elements on mobile a lot of them will use scale and translate
and it may not look as nice but that is a fact of performance so we'll take a look at one method.
However there are other methods that she could potentially use if you were seeing performance issues.
So I went and pulled a bunch of images from an splash and I'm importing them here.
I did a lot of resizing on them so that they would be performing enough to be shown in this grid view
as well as in the expanded view.
And they look just fine.
So we're going to go add a scroll view for our photo grid scroll view give it a style of stylized container
so it takes up all the available space and then it can take our images and just map over them.
Now these aren't on state.
You could do them on state if you wanted to but I'm just mapping over the images that I've imported.
If you were dynamically adding images and needing a revenger to happen then you would want them to be
on state.
So we're going to return a touchable without feedback here.
And then inside of here we're going to render an image
and give it the source
and then resize mode.
Equals cover.
Now before we refresh these We're going to be the size of the image and we want them to be grid sized
images so we're going to give it a style and give it styles a grid image and then also we could add
a content container style here on our skirl view but we'll just add another view inside here and say
style equals styles.
Grid and just wrap all of our view interviews scroll view content inside of it.
So for our grid image we'll do that one first.
We'll set up great image and we want our our images to be 3 per row.
Sordidness say with is 33 percent.
And then we'll just give it an arbitrary height of 150.
You want to calculate this based upon screen size.
But this one will work just fine and free fresh.
You can see that this is not rendering how we want it to render its rendering them the correct size
but not in the correct format.
So for our grid which is that wrapping view in our scroll view we need to say flex direction row and
if we do that we can refresh and we can see that now it's overflowing off the screen.
So we're going to need to use the wrap property and say flex wrap and wrap and now it will wrap everything
correctly in a row fashion and wrap once it exceeds the row with.
Now for this air here because we aren't actually carrying about we don't have any particular identity
for each of these images just in say key equals index.
They aren't going to be dynamic so this will be this will be fine for our purposes.
Now before we move on from the image we need to understand the concept behind what we're trying to do.
So in the reac native world you can measure these items you can measure any element that you want and
it will return the with the height and the x and y coordinates of it.
And when what we're going to do in terms of concepts is when you press on this image we're going to
dynamically measure it and receive a callback with its positioning.
Then we're going to get the measurements of this top view where the image will be Emyr going to set
the image properties the width height and the coordinates of that image.
That's going to be here to be the image that we pressed.
So we're going to need to get access to the ref of each of these images so that we can get the coordinates
and the size so that we can actually do a image swap.
This one would be hit in this one appear will be met will set its size is in its coordinates to be right
here and then we can animate it to its actual position.
And so first let's go create a component will mount lifecycle method and say this dot grid images equals
an object so that we can save off all of the references.
And then for each of these images we'll say ref an image and then we'll just say this dot grid images
and save everything off based upon the index equals image Additionally we're going to need to set up
a some sort of on press for our touch without feedback so we'll call it handle open image
which will receive the index of the image that was clicked so we can then map it back to our grid images
and then here will say on press and then call this handle open image with our index.
And so now now we're set up to receive whatever images clicked on and then do our measurements and didn't
then do our transition.
Now that we have our scroll view grid view set up we need something to transition to.
That's what the shared elements is all about.
You have a particular view and then you have a second view that you transition to.
So we're going to set up a view below our scroll view
and we're going to use our pointer events techniques are going to say style equals style sheet not absolute
fill.
And then we also need to toggle our pointer events and for our pointer events we will drive it off of
whether or not we have an active image or not.
So I'll say this that state that active image and say auto or none.
And then we are going to set up our content.
So we're going to say view here at the top our animated image will be in here.
And then our content will be done here which will be an animated view so we can kind of transition it
in once the image is selected.
For our content I'm just going to paste in a bunch of content and that way we don't have to write out
warm up some it's just going to be generic but this could be controlled by you or whatever image content
that you have to display.
And now we can get to actually styling this.
So there's a few things that we need to take care of first.
So the first one will be the style for our top content sociate style equals styles top content.
And then another crucial piece to this is that because we're going to be adjusting our animated image
I mean I want it to appear here instantly but we're going to do is get the ref of the available space.
So the view here that we're not going to animate will be taking up the space that we want to occupy
here.
And so when we do our measurements will actually measure this rapping view which we wanted to be the
same this image to be covering this.
And so that is a way that we can actually adjust our image but still get accurate measurements of the
space that we want to occupy.
So we're just going to say rough the image and this dot view image equals image and we'll just continue
to reference that as the image.
But it's actually going to be the container wrapping our image.
And now we're going to set up our animated image.
We're going to say key equals this state active image.
That way it'll just kind of clear out the cache every time we toggle.
Having an active image and an inactive image of the source to just be this state that active image.
So when we select one of these we'll just put whichever image it is on our state and then we'll say
resize mode equals cover.
This is actually a crucial bit if we want our animations to look smooth in terms of animating from one
particular scenario to the second scenario.
We either have a matching resize modes so we have a resize mode of cover on our image here and or resize
mode of image on our image here.
And that way they'll be a smooth transition and then we'll say style equals an array and we'll say styles
view image so we can style that.
And finally done here we'll add some styles to our content so a style style stot content.
And now we can go and style the top content or view image and our content down here.
Now we can apply our styling for those styles that we built there.
So we're going to say first our top content which will be the container that we're measuring So we're
going to say it's flex 1 then for our regular content we're going to say it's Flex 2 with a background
color of white and that means that this will take up some space here and this will take up twice as
much space down here.
And then for our view image because we'll be wanting it to cover and then manipulate will be manipulated
with height and the top and left.
We're just going to say WITHNALL height no position absolute and then top zero and left zero and these
will all get overwritten when we actually do our animation now before we go and we refresh let's add
state and say active image is just NULL from the beginning.
That way when we refresh it won't it all references stay and there will be an object there for us.
So now we refresh.
You can see that we have our container taking up the top available spacebar image should be.
And then we have our styling or our content down here taking up twice as much space.
Now if you feel so inclined we can go at our title style and just say font size 28 refresh and now we
have a bigger title there.
Now you'll notice that we are rendering this over the top.
However we already added our pointer events technique and because we said that our active image is no.
We don't have an active image that means all touch events will be ignored on this covering view.
So yes it's still a rendering but it won't accept any of its And we can prove that by just pressing
and scrolling you see all all such events are passing through to the content behind it which is our
scroll view and it allows us to scroll.
Now what that also means is that when we press on this image here this touch without feedback will fire
and go to our handle open image.
So that means we can start crafting the animation for our our shared element transition and before we
do that we need some animations some intermediate values to animate and so if we break this down we're
going to need a couple of different things because we're animating the width and height of the image
as well as the absolute position of our image.
We're going to need two different animated value ex-wives.
Now we could create an animated value for width and height but we're just going to use estimated value
x y because it's already a two value system.
And then also we could do an interpolation on this down here based upon the Y positioning.
But we're just going to do a separate animated value that we control and we'll do all these other animated
Vout animated transitions in sequence with the transition for this one.
So that means that we need to set up three animated values one for size would be with height which would
say is animated value x y 1:04 position which is another animated value x y and then one just general
animation and we'll initialize our animation with the value of 0.
So the first thing we can do is get this content out of the way so we're going to do it translate on
it.
So it kind of slides up when we select our image and then also in opacity on it.
So in our render we can say Konst animated content translate equal state animation does interpret our
input range of zero to 1 and our output range will move 300 down.
And then when it's active it won't be translated at all and we can then build our Konst animated content
styles and say opacity is just going to be this that state animation and then do our transform and translate
y will be animated content translate.
Now we can take this animated content styles come past into our animated content and when we refresh
we can see that our animation is gone.
Our content is gone because of the way we've set up our animations.
Now that we have our content out of the way it's ready to start doing the transition for our animated
image shared element.
So let's come up here to our handle open image and the first thing that we need to do is get access
to the ref so we can call measure on it.
Of say this dot create images index measure and that will receive a callback and give us some values.
The first one will be X Y then with height page X and Page Y and we care about with high paychecks and
Page y now because we wouldn't need our position later because once this is open we need to animate
it back to its position.
So what that means is that we need to save off our X..
Do you go to page X this dot y equals page Y and then our with and our height.
Otherwise we'd need to measure things again so we'll just save off the location of it as long as it
doesn't change.
And then because our concept is that we want to get these measurements and then swap out the active
image that's going to be here and have it have the same dimensions.
But we're going to be piping our size and position into that image that's up here and so we can just
to a set value so this set up position does set value and will say x is equal to our page X and R Y
is equal to or page Y and then the same goes for our size.
We can say this upstaters size value X will just be r with and y will be our height.
And so now we're ready to swap out the active image from null to set our image so we can say this top
set state and pass our interactive image the images index and we'll also save off the active index and
just pass an index here.
Even though we're setting this we haven't actually built the styles yet so we should actually go build
those styles before we continue on so.
Down here in our render we're going to set up two styles.
One will be our active image style and the second will be controlling the opacity on our grid image.
So the reason we needed the active index is because we need to know which image we wanted to hide.
So first let's set up our active image style.
We're going to say with this state that size X and our height of this state DOT sized Y and then our
top the state DOT position dot X or Y I should say Y and then left this state up position dot X and
then we'll set up our active index style so conc active index style.
So you go to opacity and animate this because you want it to be instance we'll say this dot state that
active image.
If we have one will say zero.
If not it will be 1 and with this we can then go pass it into our image so we're going to say Konst
style is equal to index and if our index is equal to this that state that active index then we're going
to say active index style which is hiding our opacity.
Otherwise we'll say it's undefined and we can just pass that into our image.
So now if we refresh and we press on one of these we'll see it disappear and then we can replace it
with our image.
So we press on it and it disappears.
Because we now have an active image for this particular index.
So now that we have an empty hole we need to go fill it in and see that we already have that appropriately
set up when we press on this we get its measurements we save them off for later and then we assign them
to the animated value ex-wives.
And this is happening before we actually render our image because we are then going to set our active
image to the image that we clicked.
If we pass in our active image style we've already set these dimensions to be this exact square.
So now if we take our active image style we can go and pass it into our active image so we refresh.
And in doing so when we press on this field might see a small flicker but our image will be replaced
with our top view image or active image.
And now the final step is to get the dimensions of that that wrapping view that we had up here.
And then animate our view our image I should say to the size that it will take up so with reacts.
There's a callback to set state.
This is equivalent of component did update.
And we know that that means that the image that we rendered here that active image that's in these dimensions
and replacing the actual photo great image has officially appeared and then that means that we can now
measure our view up top.
So to say this view image measure and it will take a callback just like the measure we had here and
in this case we're going to say we're going to preface everything with T.
So t x t y t with T height t page x and t page Y.
And that's just I'm just referencing it as a target and with those measurements we can now animate to
them because we already have the animated values of it's location here and now we can animate to its
final destination and everything will happen correctly and we want to have that to happen at the same
time so we can say animated up parallel takes our array.
And we'll just do a spring on all of it.
So we're going to animated that spring not state position X to value of t page X..
And then with the next one will be animated springe is that state that position Y and will be to value
T page y.
So even though we aren't yet complete with our animations Let's see if it's actually working.
Radical's start on our parallel and come back here and do a refresh.
Now what should happen is that we're going to render our image here and then animate to pay jacks and
t page Y which is the dimensions of the top content.
Now the top content page x and y is going to be 0 0.
So if we've done this correctly when we press on this it should animate from the offset here for this
particular image to 0 0.
And so we can refresh press on it and see that it does just that.
We can still see that we have that opacity on the actual image that's in the photo grid.
So now we have three more animations to do with the height and our animation for our content.
So we're going to animated that spring that state's size dot X to value of the T with which is our target
with animated Spring State sized y to value T height and then animated that spring outstate animation.
To value of one.
And now we're complete with our animation.
We're going to be able to trigger this.
It'll animate to the exact positions and our content will slide up.
Now that we're up here we need a way to close this.
So we're just going to add an X button.
So down here in our view so that it will appear above all of this.
We're going to add a touchable without feedback and we're going to wrap it in an animated view style
equals styles close and we'll need to use an opacity on this because it's going to be a part of this
view and this whole view is not being controlled with opacity just the bottom part is and then we'll
say text put an X somewhere text and we will need to give this some styling So NSA style equals styles
like close text.
So now let's set that up.
We're going to say close and we're going to a position absolute
top 20 right 20.
And then for our close text or say background color is transparent.
Font size twenty eight color white.
So if we were to refresh this our X is still appearing so we need to actually control the opacity in
regards to the animation.
So we're going to need to create a cartes animated close style and you can just pass in our opacity
with this state animation.
We take this it into our animated view.
And now when we refresh and see that it's gone from when we open up an image it appears.
However when this X is clicked we need to handle the closing of Suranne on press here.
Say this handle close
and now we can go do the reverse of our animation that we opened with.
So the reverse of our animation is going to be another parallel
and then we're going to do animate back to the position that the item in the grid was so animated timing
we're going to do a timing on this one versus a spring that set up position X to value of this dot X
which was the original grid position that we saved off of the photo and a duration of 250.
And then we can do the same thing for everything else animated that timing is tight state position y
to value this y duration to 50 and then the size and animated time in this state position or does size
X to value this stuff with duration of 250 them animated timing this state that's sized.
Why do you do this stuff right.
To ration 50 and finally to control our content as well we animate it back to zero.
So animated timing this state animation to value of zero and a duration of two hundred and fifty.
And then we need to call start on this.
However we'll notice that we don't actually have the active imagery setting.
So we'll see what that looks like in a second.
So let's refresh this.
And when we open up our image again and then we close it.
This will animate back to where it was in the grade and we can see that happening here.
However because we aren't toggling our active image the pointer events will still be set to auto.
Meaning that that active you can is clickable and are touches now won't go through to the photo grid.
And this is actually just the active image sitting in that position that that photo grid was originally
in.
So now we need to pass in a callback to our start function.
And so when this is complete we can then swap out the active image with no which trigger we render the
original image and this position will be go from opacity of zero to 1 and then our pointer events will
toggle so we can click on the photo grid items again.
So now we can refresh open up an image close it animates down and we can continue to do that for other
and other images even ones that we've scrolled to we've swapped over to Android because we want to show
what this code would actually do on Android.
So first off we're going to copy and paste iOS and paste it into the Android side.
Save this and we're going to refresh and when we press on this we see it nothing happens and there are
a few things there that we need to debug.
So there are two ways to get access to the lay out of a particular view and that is with onlly out and
also calling measure on RF.
One of the things that I found was an issue with Android was that even though we had reference to our
our image and called measure there were no values that were coming back for the width height or the
page X and Page y.
So I just added an on layout and added an empty function that got called.
And this would tell Briac that we needed to get access to those measurements to now and refresh and
click on an image.
It kind of works.
However note that it's not a smooth transition if you press on one down here it still will animate to
the position that's inside.
And the reason why that is is because there is no overflow visible available on Android.
And so it's trying to animate outside of the container of our container here that we're measuring but
it's not able to because it is there is no overflow visible and it's hidden.
So it's going beyond here trying to estimate back down but it's getting caught outside of this when
it tries to go outside this view.
So to fix this all we have to do is actually move it to the root view so move it to this root container.
And because we aren't actually animating this container here but it still is the thing that we're measuring
we can animate something into that space.
So if we remove our animated image here and we move it into the root container the same will need to
happen for our clothes.
So now we see that clothes hidden because we have hot relisting enabled we can move this out here
and now it appears that this is actually sitting outside of our view container.
So if we refresh and we press on one of these images we can now see that because it's its parent is
this entire screen that the overflow visible will work just fine or the image will animate just fine.
If we press on it and see that it animates to the available space this flex container is inside of our
view but it's saving us a spot where we can animate our image too and then we can close this animates
right back just like it was on.
Working well on iOS.
So sometimes for Android you do have to do some hacks but we kind of set it up perfectly so that we
have an empty space that is a space saver we can move our image and structure things correctly so that
it is capable of animating without and kind of doing a work around with the limits on overflow on Android.