This is another animation found on you eye movement.
You can see that we have a sort of color picture here.
And when we press on the color there's an expansion out.
We can download the gift here from dribble after pressing on it and it is made by Nick Frost.
So in our actual animation we won't be modifying the text color bold italic or any of that kind of stuff
that can be implemented by you and is beyond the scope of this animation tutorial.
But if we pop open we can see that the animation actually starts at this are really being open and we
get to action and we can step through so we can see here that decompose what's happening we've pressed
on it and this square stays in both views and doesn't change which means that there is likely a container
view here that contains both the pulled icon and the headings and all that kind of a button action as
well as contains the button that's slowly popping out here.
So you can see that it starts with a small button and then it slowly scale up.
When you see that frame by frame that the input is already there and so we are slowly expanding this
covering box out.
Well these are already there so we know that there's going to be two views one is going to be sitting
over the top and then there's one going to be sitting on the bottom which contains our buttons.
We can keep slow the scaling that button out until our other icons are completely covered.
Now we don't need to deal with the reverse because we could just use a 1 zero with inter-relations and
have a reversible animation.
But now let's take a look at what the close looks like.
So here you can see that we are stepping through and that the box here is slowly fading and collapsing.
So the outside box is actually causing is actually pulling in.
And those bold icons and all that kind of stuff is staying in place.
Now this may be slightly difficult to do but we can kind of recreate the same exact effect.
Also we scroll back we can see that there is a slight translate and scale happening.
So it was in one spot and it slowly is shrinking and moving towards the hello world.
And see here now the gap is almost completely gone.
It's now inside and kind of behind it.
And now it's completely gone.
So that's likely just a translate and an opacity on the outside.
However we're going to add a different effect with a translate and a scale.