For our color picker we're going to need to set up two new animated components.
The first thing will be our animated text input.
And the second will be animated icon that we've imported from Riak the vector icons and using the foundation
icons set.
We already just have our buttons set up that will call handler toggle to get us going with an open inclosing
function call in our animation breaktime we could see that when it opened up that would be a single
animation to go from nothing to something.
And so that was reversible so that now that means we know that we need a single animation of-I for that.
And then additionally there was a second open and close with the input and the button that seemed reversible.
So we should set up two different animations so do state equals animation animated value and that will
be for the toggling open and closed.
And then we'll do a button animation and that will be for when we open up the button and the input there
thing we need do is use to find our color on our state.
So going to default to black and that will be for the drive the value in the input.
Before we start driving any animations let's first get our viewers set up.
This is something that people may not realize but if you build your view then creating the animations
to go from different states is a lot easier.
So we're going to set up an animated view.
So we are wrapping view I want to say style equals styles dot row wrap.
Now let's go define our style.
So include a row rap style and because our items are moving in a row direction we need to switch our
flex direction to row for this.
Then we're going to align our items to the center so that they are centered along the horizontal line
then we're going to say menwith of 50 percent.
So at least take up 50 percent of our screen so that our background color to white sort of border radius
of 20 so the edges will be rounded.
Sort of a shadow color.
Dark gray shadow opacity point to shadow offset.
X too wide to
shadow radius 3 and we'll add some padding and so will do a padding vertical of five and a padding horizontal
of 10.
Now these values I arrived just kind of playing with stuff and seeing what it looked like.
And so because there's no content in it we just have this very thin box that is the spacing is our padding.
And now we can start filling in our our icons with our colored ball.
It needs to be separate.
And then there needs to be a separate container for both the buttons and the
button and its inputs.
So why don't we set up a color ball first.
So we're going to your color ball and we'll give it with 15 a high of 15 and a border radius of eight.
And that way it will be a perfect circle.
And then we can come up here and say touchable without feedback because we are going to want to be able
to touch this and trigger some sort of event to happen.
And then inside of here we're going to create an animated view and pasand style and new styles.
What color ball
Additionally we want the background color of our ball to be driven based upon state.
So we're going to to create a style we'll just create a contrast color style equals background color
and this state color and how we can pass this in and if we refresh.
So we now have our 15 by 15 ball and it's black driven based upon our state.
So with this we now need to create another view to the right of it.
So when would say View style equals styles row so we can style this row and this will be the container
for both our buttons and for our button and input.
So to save a little bit of time I'm just going to paste in all the buttons that I have and they're are
going to be wrapped in touchable pasties because you just want to show that they can still be triggered.
And then we're going to use our animated icons because we want to animate these later.
So if we save this and refresh you'll see that we are in a calm fashion for our row.
So we need to now go tile our rows.
It will be appropriately the appropriate direction.
So we're going to create a row here
and inside of this we're going to build a flex one so it'll take up all of the available space.
We're not going to do a line items center and then justify content to space around so that there's even
space around each of the icons.
They're going to do flex action row.
So they're in a row.
It's dialing.
And then we're just going to give it overflow.
Hidden.
Now when you refresh we have appropriate spacing between each of the icons and they're each touchable
and they're in the center aligned with our colorable.
So now that we have the icons let's add the input and the button right over the top of the icon so that
we know all of the pieces that we have to animate So that will be in this container here.
Because we'll need to animate the outside of the container.
We're going to make it an animated view.
And we'll be able to put our animated text input in there as well as our touchable without feedback.
Which will drive our animated view which will be our button
and then it will have some text that says OK
for our rapping or our animated view that wraps all of this we're going to give it a style to use the
style sheet talk absolute fill.
Now that this is below our buttons and covering the entire view our entire row view if we go back here
and see that we can't actually touch anything because it's covering all of this.
So that means that when we have two views rendering we're going to need to use our pointer events technique
to toggle whether or not this you can receive touches or not.
So first let's style our color row wrap.
We're going to pass it styles color row wrap and then let's go add those and will say color wrap and
we're going to make it flex direction row so it's the same as everything else.
Flex 1 and then just on the left side to where the color ball is we can see that it's right up against
that color ball string and say padding left five.
So now if we refresh we can see that the input has no spacing.
And then our ok is button right there should say that our.
Our input has no layout no sizing.
So we're going to give it some size which to say flex 1 and say take up of the space.
And because it this be in the same container as our ok button.
We can just give our ok button.
Some specific styling we're going to give it a border radius of 20 with a width of 40 so that it's a
circle and to have a height of 100 percent to take up all up and down.
Area going at a background color of 3 0 9 Eby which is the blue color.
And then we're going to these line items center and justify content center to center our text and then
for our Okay text are just the same color white.
So sometimes I do this whenever I set up my views.
I'll just run through and figure out exactly what stylings need to happen to those views to make them
stack correctly once they're there.
Once I have rendered them so pass and our style equals styles the input and this is going to be our
style equals styles that OK button.
And then this is in the style equals styles.
OK.
Text and now when we refresh.
We kind of have everything laid out correctly.
Our input is right here taking up all the available space and then our button is defined over here.
Now that we have all of our views set up we can now start doing the transitions with our animations.
The first thing I'll do is just the toggling of this entire thing.
So we're going to come up to our handle toggle say conc to value.
So you could do this to square open zero or one is going to store the toggling of it on the component
instance.
The reason why is we only care about the pointer events technique for this one which with the pointer
events technique we need to store a particular value on state to trigger a rear under cover in our case
we don't care whether or not this thing is open enough then we'll do an animated spring on this state.
Animation to value and call start and then we will toggle this dot open equals not this dot open the
animation will now all run off of interpellation.
Which means that it will be completely reversible.
So now we need to set up our conc Rowe style and we'll just right off the bat at a few different things
driven off of 0 to 1.
So the things driven off of 0 to 1 will be our opacity.
So zero it will be hidden and at 1 it will be visible and then we'll add in or transform and we'll pass
and a translate or scale Y and past and see the animation so it will scale the y from here to here correctly
and then we need to control the scale x which will then be the width and height expansion.
And then also the movement from down here to look like it's erupting from the button.
So now with just these two animations if we take our pro-style and pass it into our VRO
and then we'll refresh and then trigger this and see that it just kind of has a opacity and it's Calle
y kind of rotate effects.
However we want it to start from the button and explode out and explode.
Up and out.
So we're going to define our Konst scale x inter-relate and this be this animation to interpolate this
back
and our input range will define as zero point five and 1.
So we do a point five click here so that we will execute the x direction of our scale until after half
the animation is completed.
So a passenger input range 0 0 and then 1.
So let's pass a Senate and see what effect that has had.
So skill X
be fresh.
Watch the watch it here.
So we see that it is scaling it's Y and then it's X is moving it from the center outwards.
Then finally we need to set up our scale wise and say conc or translate why I should say translate.
Why interpolate because of this Up-State animation.
Interpolate input range 0 to 1 in our output range at zero.
We want it to be moved down roughly here so about 150 and then once it hits one meaning it's open.
We don't want it to be anything we want it to be sitting right up here.
So we can take that precedents to translate.
Why.
And now to refresh we toggle it it move from here and explode upwards and outwards
and now we need to define and work with hiding this input and this button.
So we're going to set up a contest move and interpolate and operate off of the button animation.
I know we haven't animated this yet but we'll set it up and then we'll control our animation later.
So they're going to interpret and this will be an input range of 0 to 1 as well.
And our output range will be starting at negative 115 moving to zero.
This will be passed into a translate X sort of move it roughly over here somewhere so that we have the
button kind of explode out towards zero which is in its position now so say cartes button style equal
to transform.
And the first way to translate x to a person or move interpolate and then to also make it small and
then scale out to its normal size pasand scale and passages state button animation because already moving
from 0 to 1.
So with this button style Let's go ahead and pass that in to our button down here which is here and
our touch type feedback animated view.
So because we have one animation already set up let's go trigger what happens when we press on our animated
colored ball here.
So that's just going to be a function called toggle input and here will do a very similar thing to what
we did up above where it is a contest to value equals this dot and put Open 0 and 1 and we'll also save
up the input open on our state in a second.
But we're going to just worry about that later.
The animated timing does not state that button animation to value duration of 350 milliseconds we'll
call start and then we'll toggle this input open to not start input input open.
Now that we have this toggle input function come down to our colorable with a touch without feedback
we'll say on press equal to this total input and now we refresh this and we open it up our button is
now gone.
Our input still there but if we trigger our button animation we can see that our ball explodes from
somewhere around here into its original position or its layout position.
Now we're going to deal with our text input.
We haven't actually completed setting up our text input.
We're gonna need to pass in the value which we have on this state color.
We're going to have to pass in something to update the state so on change text.
Now give us a text value and say this does set state
and then here we're going to get our ref to our input so that afterwards we can actually focus on it.
So the users can type it in as well as potentially blur after the fact to say this input is equal to
input.
So there we have that set up a free refresh and open this up so that we have our color sitting right
here and if we add to it it changes to blue or whatever color we type in.
And now we can control the animation for our enemy to text input which is just going to be an opacity
animation once or button kind of expands past all available text that could be input.
Real slow will fade it in pretty quickly.
So let's come up here and do an interpolation on our button animation.
Scott's input opacity and interpolate of this state animation button animation we want to operate off
our button animation and interpret passenger input range and zero.
When you say point eight point Cliff to one that are output range will be 0 0 and then 1.
So that way it's hidden for about 80 percent of the animation.
And then will quickly appear.
And now we can craft our input Silas's at concerts and put style Sugata opacity passenger input opacity
and interpolate.
And then we can bring it down here to our animated text input and we'll combine these and when we refresh
and open this up see that our input is gone.
And then when we chigger our animation here it fades in.
Once this is kind of gone by it.
And then also the reverse so rather than just adding a white background to our color wrap row you're
going to actually hide and move are touchable are animals and icons so it looks like they are actually
animating in the opposite direction as our expanding button.
So let's come up here and we're going to set up an interplay.
Say Konst icon translate because of this state button animation and interpolate an input range.
We'll have to go from 0 to 1 but we're going to be doing reverse values so at zero we don't want our
thing to do anything.
And then as we animate open our button we want to move it negative 20 and then we'll do an inter-relate
for the opacity as well.
We'll say Konst opacity Ican interpret this state animation button animation that interpolate put on
input range and we'll just go from zero to point two.
So this will happen very quickly.
This will happen in the first 20 percent of our animation output range which would be one of the visible
when the button is closed and then hidden when it's opening.
And then you can extrapolate clamp and then we'll create our cost icon style pastie can be opacity.
I kind of interpolate and a translate X for a transform
like X and pass in our icon translate.
Now we can apply this to each of our icons.
So we're going to say style equals icon style.
Just copy and paste this and put it on all of the icons.
And now refresh this open and then watch the icons as the button moves.
And comes back.
So they kind of shift and fade out and look like they're swapping places with that expanding button
and view.
Finally we need to do one more thing.
And if you notice here yes these buttons are visible.
However we can't actually touch on them because we are wrapping it and covering it with this absolute
filled view.
So we need to control the pointer events on our animated view here.
So we're going to add pointer events and say this state that input open which we haven't created yet.
If it is open to say Otto otherwise and I say none and we can come up to our input open or our state
and input open and it will default to false.
Now in order to have that take effect read it come down here and say this dot set stay.
This is going to be our target input say input.
Open is equal to this dot underscore and put open.
So now we refresh target open we can press on our buttons and when we open this up they're gone.
Go back
and they're good to go.
Finally for accessibility purposes we want to focus and blur this text input once the animation is complete.
So we're actually going to do a callback here which is a component to it update callback.
And that way we know that the focus where we know that the pointer events will be able to allow this
thing to be touched.
So to say if not this does stay open and we do this not because we're actually sugaring and not here
so we're doing a double knot but if it's not open anymore and that should be input open if it's not
open any more than we say this underscore input which is our raft our input because it's an animated
input.
We're going to say get node Blar And then if we are open which is this second parameter to this ternary
here and I say this does underscore input get node and then focus what this is going to do for us is
when we open this up and click on our colorable we're going to have focus on the field.
And then when we close it we're going to blur the focus on the field.
So if we have our keyboard open now it's open and then close it and the keyboard goes away.
And one other thing we can do is come down to our touch both feedback on the OK button and pass it on
press calls this toggle input for refresh in our press on this.
And it will hide everything.
So some of the key kind of takeaways from this is make sure that you have all the lay out set out for
your view and then just reverse each piece at a time until you have the animation that you've desired
for opening closing and anything else in between.
And then also make sure that buttons continue to be touchable and use pointer events when you need to.