A popular animation is a floating action button with a menu kind of behind it.
In our case we have the Starbucks application and when you press on the button the PE text will pop
out as those two buttons will pop out with order and reload text.
Take a look at this animation and break it down and you can see that when we press our pay button let's
focus on the two icons.
First the two other menu items the order and the reload are basically already off set and they scale
up from 0 to 1 at a particular point.
And then the order reload and pay about halfway through the animation will explode out from kind of
inside of the button out towards position left.
Finally there is the background.
The background is a circle and it expands outwards and covers the entire screen and it's black with
some opacity so you can still see the background.