We're going to build our fab animation in a reversible fashion.
That just means we have a single animated value that we animate from 0 to 1 and everything interpolates
correctly.
So to get started we'll set up our state but the single animation value I would just set at 0 also to
get access to some icons we're going to pull and reacting to vector icons with material community icons.
Feel free to look at the documentation for reacting to vector icons to set that up.
It's just 22:00 install and then a reactive link and you're good to go.
The first thing we need to do is set up our pay button and that's going to be in the bottom right corner
and we're going to use touchable without feedback for this.
That way our button is not affected by the wrapping animated view or anything in that way we can style
our button and absolute position at the bottom right corner.
So I give in on press and just call this toggle open.
We haven't created that yet.
And then we'll set up a view
and we'll need to style that view.
Now for that view we're going to need to create a button style and we want this to be reusable so that
the other two buttons can also apply it.
And then because there is the difference with that green button will also have to apply some sort of
pay styling so that we can add that color and so is his style is equal to styles dot button and then
styles that pay.
So now let's build our styling for our buttons so that we can set up ourselves for our other buttons.
So with this button we'll give it a width of 60 a height of 60 we will align our items to the center
and justify our content that way any icon in the middle of it all will appear in the middle of it.
Add shadow color should be this dark black gray shadow opacity will be point 1 shadow offset will do
x to y 0 than a shadow radius of 2.
And then so we have a rounded button will give it a border radius of 30 which is half of our width and
our height.
And then we'll position it absolutely and bottom 20 right 20.
So that'll take our button and move it to about right here so that it's 20 and 20 away and has a shadow.
Now if you were to use this on Android you'd have to add an elevation to accomplish that style that
shadow styling.
So let's fix a mistake and add a comma here so that our share of offset will work and then our page
styling.
And so our pay is just going to be adjusting the background color because we already have all of the
layout and all of the structure of the button here.
So our pace styling at our background color and it's going to be 0 0 1 5.
So now when we refresh and see that we have a green button appearing in the bottom right corner looking
at the break down video we saw that the center of our content is text and the others were icons.
So here we'll just go add text and say $5
and then we need to give this a styling so we'll say styles paid text go add that styling in
and all we need to do is change the color to white and I want to refresh button with $5 in the middle
of it.
So now we need to work on the other buttons.
We won't worry about the tax for now we'll just get the buttons rendering and then we can add in the
text later so we can come up here and we'll just add in some touchable without feedback's and this will
be the reload button.
So we'll say animated
view because we'll be adjusting this and translating it up and scaling it as well.
And of course we'll give it a style style button because you've already built out that styling.
And then because we'll need to adjust the background we'll give it a style other so we can then go redefine
our background and then for it's icon an icon from our material icons name equals reload with a size
of 20.
And then we'll give it a color of 5s
now we are rendering this above our bottom button because these are all going to be positioned absolutely
with the same exact shadow and the same exact positioning right behind our green button.
And we don't want them to be visible until we need them to be visible.
So we're going to copy and paste this one up above and I'm going to call it food fork drink.
It's going to be the exact same and we'll adjust the styling later.
So we have two buttons and we're adding this styles not other let's go at that is just going to be setting
the background color to white.
And when we refreshed this so that nothing happens because it is behind it.
However if we were to go and say do a transform and translate this negative 70 and refresh we see that
we have now our buttons moved up but we do this via animation.
I was just proving that we actually have our buttons that are sitting right behind our pay button.
So with hiding behind our pay button that just means that we don't have to use opacity or anything like
that.
They're just they're just hidden and will move out from behind our pay button.
But we could potentially add an opacity to have it fade in while it's moving up and scaling but that's
unnecessary.
So now it's time to tackle our styling for our reload button and our order button.
So because we want this to be reversible everything's operating off of an input range of 0 to 1 and
we'll tackle our scale.
Interpellation first so that's just going to be operating off of this state DOT animations we don't
even interpolate from it but we can set up our conc reload style and do a transform and fast and scale
and in this state animation and then Konst order style transform scale.
This state animation now we are passing in our animation knowing that this animated value will only
go between 0 and 1.
But just understand that if there is any chance that that animated value will go be on one or below
zero we should use an inter-relate for this even though it be an interpellation.
It would be interpolate input range 0 1 output range 0 1 and then crucially we would do and extrapolate
clamp that way our button would never scale beyond 1 or 0.
So even though the output range in the input range are exactly identical.
This will always make sure that that value stays between 0 and 1.
But because we know what our animated value is going to do we're not going to do that here.
Now add our second transform which will be our translate y.
So with our translate y for our order style this will be the first button that slides up here.
And then our other one will be up here and we can input.
We can do our interpolate
input range 0 to 1 and then our output range will be zero.
And because we're moving up it will be negative 70.
And this is because our button is 60 and we'll just give yourself 10 pixels of padding away from this
button here and we can copy this and give it to our order styling and instead of 70 we'll just double
that to 140.
So with our scale and translate y set up we can come down here and pass it into our animated views.
So this one would be our order style and this one will be our reload style and if we refresh here so
that nothing has happened because this is still zero.
But if we flip our default to 1 so our interpretations will kick in and we refresh.
We see that they are now spread out appropriately so with a versatile animations sometimes you might
want to test out your animation just that things are in the appropriate place.
Once you hit one so you can always toggle your default value.
So I'll just move this back to zero and hide everything.
Now let's go ahead and trigger our animation our touch without feedback pay button is calling toggle
open.
So we will create a function called toggle open and we'll just do a simple timing animation.
We'll keep track of whether or not this is open.
We don't need to use state here because we aren't doing any sort of pointer events or anything that
requires a real render.
So vulgar and get are to value and this does open even though we haven't defined it.
So it's always going to be false to start.
And then if it's open then we'll go to zero.
If it's not up and then we'll go to one.
And that way we can just do our innovative timing I send this out say to animation to value the duration
of 200 and then call start and then we'll just toggle our animation this equals not this dot open
because this is all synchronicity not going through set state we can't hammer on our button and it will
continually go up and out up and back so we can see that it doesn't matter at what point that I press
it.
The animation will stop and start moving towards the other direction either 0 or 1.
Every time we press on this so we have two things left to tackle the first is the text for here and
the second is the blackish sea through background that explodes from the button and comes up here.
So let's tackle the text first.
We're going to add some animated text because we need to move it inside of each of our buttons.
And this one will be order
inside here animated attacks will be reload and inside this button here.
Will be pay.
Now we aren't just going to go with the default styling will give this some style because it's going
to be sitting on a black background.
And so we'll get that to label and we'll go ahead and apply this to each of our animated techs.
And then go and create our styling.
Now this would have been easier if we already had our background color set with black.
We could do that really quickly by just changing this container to our G.P.A. 000 point five which is
what the background color will be.
When we eventually go to our payment animation for our background but we'll set up our labels here so
say laved color
position.
Absolute.
So that way it's independent of anything inside of here.
We'll get a font size of 18 and then background color of transparent
so that we have that so that we can go and remove whatever the background will be when that is actually
floating over here.
And now the key piece is our animation.
So we're going to set up the same animation for all of them.
That means we just need one label style that we can apply to all of them because they will be doing
the same exact animation.
And the first thing we need to do is control the positioning of our label is they translate X that comes
from about here and explodes out here kind of towards the end of the animation.
So we'll set up a label position and chirpily an equal to this animation inter-relate with an input
range of zero to one and our output range will start at negative 30 which with translate X means it's
moving this direction.
And then we'll finish at negative 90.
So this will be a slow movement from here to here.
Now the key piece of this is that we won't actually show up until the 80th percent of the animation.
So give it to our capacity.
Here say it's animation not inter-relate and will create a point eight cliff.
So we will do as zero point eight.
And because our animation is 0 to 1 This means that its covering 80 percent of the animation and then
we'll do a one here.
And our output range will be 0 0 and then 1.
So that means that from zero to 80 percent of the animation our label will be hidden.
However it will still be casually moving towards negative 90 and then it will very quickly fade in.
Over the last 20 percent of our animation so we can set that up with opacity fastener opacity and interpolate
transform and will pass and it translate acts with the label physician interplay.
So with this crafted we can apply it to all of our animated teks
save that and refresh this and will give it a shot so we can press on this and we can't see our So let's
add back our background color
refresh again.
We kind of see that it is moving very quickly and then will fade in kind of looks like it explodes.
We could you could adjust the opacity to be less than 80 percent if you wanted to see it kind of come
out of the button.
So we started that 20 percent.
You can kind of see it's Galan And now here move in and out but we'll leave it at that point at.
So the final thing to do is our background color actually being exploded from this button and we can
do that by adding an animated view above all of these.
That way it will sit behind it and the buttons will appear on top of it.
And this is going to be an animated view and we won't have any children.
We'll give some styles MySpace tiles.
Background and we're going to pass on some animated styling here eventually.
And for our backgrounds
we're going to give it the exact same positioning and as this button here that way it will actually
sit behind all of our buttons.
So first thing is the background color Well actually use RGV.
0 0 0 point 2 but you can adjust the capacity to your liking position.
Absolute with 60 height 60 bottom 20 right 20 and border radius of 13.
Now you could adjust this button to have a reusable style that's like a position or something but we
just will just type this out.
Let's fix this missing quote here before we do any sort of refreshing.
And now when we refresh.
See that nothing is changed.
This button is covering up all of our other content that we will eventually display when our animation
triggers
the final thing to do is set up our scale animation.
So we don't need to move the button at all.
We just need to scale the animation out so that they can speed dial give this a transform or scale here
and then say this state that animation interpolate input range 0 to 1 in our output range will be zero
to a very large number.
So you could calculate the required number here by taking the size of our button which is 60 and the
size of the screen and roughly dividing it by two or so that way when our scale happens it will expand
the circle outwards and cover up to the screen will also expand the other direction you just won't see
it.
So let's pass this into our background and refresh.
And now when you press on it and see that we have our expanding background and at the same time these
will slide out and scale out and these will kind of explode out.
And 80 percent until that 80 percent will be hidden and we can target them as much as we want because
it is that reversible animation.