Many applications come with an introduction and we can see here there's this library called Riak native
app intro that allows you to build out introductory animation screens.
This is great.
However if you don't understand the animations behind what's happening it may be slightly confusing.
So let's take a look at what we are going to build.
Rather than focusing on all sorts of different types of screens we're going to use the same three icons
as we say swipe through our screens.
So if you look here we can see that while we drag that this seems to be moving quicker than these others.
As we drag to the right and come back it seems to be moving left and right so we know that there's going
to be some sort of translate in a negative direction this way as we move our scroll view.
And because we are using a scroll of view and know that we're going to access the on scroll probably
with animated events and getting the content offset X..
Once we know that we're animating with the content offset we know that we're going to be building our
interpretations based upon the screen with our input range will be from here to here.
And then also if we want to do other different types of animations we might define different entries
while we are moving from either a left hand side or right hand side from the next screen and we'll take
a look at what that is right here.
So if we anime into the next screen from the left side we can see that this faded in and moved moved
from the bottom up.
Now when we transition onto the next screen you can see that we can define different animations based
upon the way that you're scrolling and that is now moving up and fading out.
Now for this animation you can see that a scale and rotate is happening.
Now we can see that it moves from a starting position of a small scale for both of the main image and
the floating image there and scales up and rotates into position.
When we get to the end of a scroll of view in iOS there is always a bounce that can potentially happen.
And if we think about doing an interpellation you must always think of.
Extrapolate now the default to extrapolate is extend and if we extend our animation be beyond what we
might have defined we would expect the animation to continue and because we are going from a small scale
to a larger scale and the content OFSAA is increasing then if we didn't define a secondary transition
then this sort of domain image and the other image would grow larger on the scale however they are growing
smaller so we know that there is a separate animation defined or separate extended input range to an
output range to handle this bounce here.