Many applications have animated intros usually images or some sort of effect that is happening while
the user is scrolling in between each of the pages will be building out the same exact page using the
same exact images.
We'll just be changing the animation.
The point of this will be to understand how to develop animations based upon scroll views while they're
scrolling.
We'll close this.
It will come down to our render function and first thing we need to do is set up a scroll view.
So we'll use scroll of you
and will then add a few different properties on it to make it work for us.
The first will give it a style style container and this will just apply our flex 1 to it so it takes
up the entire screen.
Well then also at paging enabled paging enabled will make pages based upon either the width and height
of the Scroll of view.
So in our case we will flip it to horizontal.
So because it's taking up the entire screen our pages will be the width of the screen.
So each page that we put below us will be the full width of the page.
The screen here.
So we then will add scroll of throttle and give it 16 milliseconds and then we'll need to pipe our on
scroll into an animated value.
We don't have one yet so let's go create one.
So we'll just say state to animation.
New animated value.
And we'll just defaulted to zero.
Then we will do our own scroll and it will pass and are animated that event which takes an array of
values and we want to use the first one which is the native events will need to pass in an object though
so it will traverse the object for our content so native event then the content offset.
And then because we're scrolling horizontal We want the X to be piped into this outstate animation.
So now that we have our scroll view set up we don't have any content to scroll through.
So now we need to go set up our screens for our screens.
We'll need to use width and height of the window.
So we'll use our dimensions column will say cartes width and height.
The structure that calls dimensions does get window.
Now for our first screen we'll set up a view in a style and we'll just pass in our with our height and
then a background color which we'll say is F-8 9 20 which is the orange color that we saw earlier and
will close off our view.
So now we have a single page ready to receive content that is the entire width and the entire height
which is also equivalent to the paging enabled width and height that it has determined.
So now all of our pages will lock correctly to each particular screen.
The screen usually consists of a header and some text so the top part might be a bunch of images and
the bottom might be some instructional text or some other actions.
So set up our view in two different pieces we have a view here and a view here we'll just put some text
here.
Colts green one and will in our images up here but we'll need to give these some styling so we're going
to say style equals style Start screen Hetter and style Eco's styles screen text but that will just
be a flex one so we use our container again actually to be explicit just which is to screen text and
we'll add in screen Hetter which we flex one line items sensor and justify content center and are screen
texts we'll say is flexible and to take up even amounts of space.
So now if we refresh this we have a orange background and our screen one is appearing here and now we
have a content container appear to add images to now that we have our containers we're going to add
an anchor image.
This will just be an image without any absolute positioning that is just to the line items and justify
content and sit right in the middle.
So we're going to give it an animated image.
And to say the source is equal to images.
Image one.
And then some styling to define the width and height and then resize mode.
We're going to say is contain
within this image may have a particular size that we want and to maintain that across densities of the
screen we need to use the pixel ratio get pixel size for layout size and then pass in our desired size
good for multiply by the pixel density depending on the type of phone that you have.
So this 75 might become something a lot larger than 75 on a two and a half pixel density phone.
Now we'll pass in here as well and say pixel ratio get pixel out for size and pasand 63.
So now we have a singular image rendering and we can go to refresh and then we have our anchor image
that we can now decorate other potential animated images on top of it to save some time and in our images
and just go over them real quick.
We have our images too.
This is the one that we will be animating which is why we have an array here so we can pass in an estimated
value styling and then we have our third one here so to refresh nothing happens because it didn't save
it.
Now I want to refresh.
See that they're appearing in relatively appropriate locations up here in our render Barry would typically
start defining our content.
This could be kind of overwhelming so we're going to create separate functions and then pass it the
animation and the width and have it return our styling for us.
So where does that screen one Stiles is equal to get screen 1 Stiles.
We're going to pass it what we need so the state animation and then because we are the paging is of
the width and that's what you're operating off of.
And we're going to need to define our input ranges using the width of our scroll view which is the width
of our windows to Will the past in our with.
And now we get to go make our function our Get screen 1 stylus function which will do up here.
So they can't get screen size equals animation.
And with and we'll do our aero function.
Now it is very important to define our input ranges correctly typically because we have an array of
screens or multiple screens.
The input ranges would likely be automatically calculated based upon the index that we were rendering
things in.
We're going to do it explicitly so that we all understand exactly where the values are coming from for
the input range.
In our case we're just going to animate this image to hear sort of say Cotts image to translate X we'll
just move it side to side and turn off our animation and then we'll define our input range our input
range will be we'll take three values generally one value for when you're moving towards a stable position
the value for when you're at a stable position.
And then what to do when you're moving away from a stable position.
And when I say stable position I just mean that there is a position where the pages have stopped which
in our case on the first screen it stops on zero so a stable position of not moving is zero.
However our movement away is as the scroll view moves this way.
The x will increase towards the width.
And this with is actually the next screens stable position.
This will become more apparent on our second screen.
So now the passen output range I will say when we're stable we want zero translate.
But as we move away.
So as we move to the next screen we want to translate negative 100 which is just to the left.
And then we'll extrapolate clamp here.
If we don't extrapolate clamp we don't really have control over the width of our scroll view.
So we want to lock it to exactly the input range that we've defined otherwise this will can continue
on to much higher than negative 100.
And then we'll just pass back some styling so we'll say return image to and we'll add a transform array
of objects and or translate X will be image to translate x.
So now down here in our screen one styles we can pass this in to our image to here so image.
So even though we don't have any other content there's still a bounce that will happen and allow us
to overextend our scroll of view content.
So let's refresh this.
And we can see if her animation is working as we grab our screen and drag it we can see if you watch
that image to begin can see that it's actually doing it's translate X away.
So it's not actually staying in the same position and then as I release and it moves back towards the
zero the scroll content offset moves back towards zero.
You can see that this will move to its stable position at zero.
Translate so because we want to focus on our animations we're just in a copy and paste this first screen
and paste it three different times the screen three
will be screened too and we'll go replace the screen one style and this one as well defined separate
styles for each of the screens.
So now we need to go define two other screen styles.
So we're going to say cartes screen two styles ECOs get screen two styles and will once again pass in
this state the animation and with and then conc screen three styles because get screen three styles
pass in our animation and are with.
And now we need to go make these sort of make these functions so that if we refresh we won't get any
errors.
So can't say that cause animation with and then can't skip screen three styles.
Animation and with so let's focus on our second screen now.
So we're going to do two different animations.
One will be an entrance animation and the second will be an exit animation.
So that means we need to craft our input range correctly.
So they just define our input range here as an array and we'll walk through it.
So because we'll be on our second screen so it's refreshed as a move towards our second screen as we
move towards it.
That's going to be when it's coming from the previous page which is over here to its stable position
which is the left side of the screen here which is an offset of a single with so one with has passed
this first screen one screen has passed.
So that means in order to do an animation we need to define our our input range from the previous stable
position which was zero for the first screen to the stable position that we have here which is this
a singular width of the screen.
So we're going to say zero for the previous stable.
And then with for what our current stable is then to define our exit animation we can do something different.
So what we're going to do is animate this one in an animated up and out.
However this is going to go from the stable position.
So that's what our current middle and put range value is to the stable position of our next screen and
it's screen 3 but with a zero base index it's going to be the with times 2 because we've gone by two
separate screens.
So here we're going to say with times 2 and now we can define an entrance animation via the output range.
What this stable value is in the output range so likely zero.
And then here will define how the animation should exit as it moves on to screen 3.
So now we can define our animations.
So say Konst image to translate.
Why.
Because the animation interpolates in our input range.
Well the finer output range as we'll start a 100 down when we're stable we're going to be at zero translate
so it'll be in its normal position.
And then as we move away to the next screen we'll continue the animation upwards.
So negative 100 so slide so this screen here will slide from here to here.
And then as we go to the third screen from here to here we'll also do an extrapolate clamp that's going
to be very important to keep doing extrapolate clamp.
Otherwise this will just continue to flow all the way up here.
We'll also define some opacity so say contest image to opacity animation in Triple-A put her input range
in.
So these are the same input ranges they're just driving different animations for output range will say
we're we're zero we're hidden as we slowly move more stable we fully we'll have a full opacity at the
Staple Mark.
And then as the inmate away it'll move towards not stable and will add extrapolate clamp even though
this one is kind of unnecessary.
And then we will return our styling so return image to opacity image to opacity transform and translate
why hoby image to translate.
Why.
So now that we're loading that up we can come down here and we'll go to our second screen and then we
will pass in our image to our screen to styles to image to and will refresh this.
And we'll see.
So have our first animation because it's running on the same animation but a different interplay on
different input ranges.
As we slowly slide over here we can see that our second image is about 100 down as we're slowly sliding.
And it's has a somewhat animation or opacity between 0 and 1.
And then once we fully reach our stable position it's now at zero for a translate y and one for its
opacity.
And then as we move towards our third screen now it's moving up and fading out.
And then when we move backwards that's going to start from the top and move down because that's how
we defined our input ranges.
And then same back to square one.
Get back to that original position.
Now let's define our third screen which will do two different animations.
The first one we need to do is define our input range so our input range once again is going to be previous
stable current stable and next stable.
So the previous stable was screen 1 or screen 2 which meant the stabilization was with then our current
stable is that screen 3 is with times 2.
That's the current offset.
So we have one screen here and one screen here and this is the left hand position and then with times
three would be the stable position of the fourth screen.
If we had a fourth screen now we'll just set up scale and rotate.
So would you Kautz image scale.
So the animation done interpolate input range output range will be 0 1 and then 0 and we'll do and extrapolate
clamp here.
That will set up a rotating image to rotate with the animation and interpolate input range output range
will say is negative 180 degrees 0 degrees at our rest.
And then as we move away rotate continue to rotate towards 180 degrees and once again extrapolate clamp.
So it doesn't just keep doing a full 360 degree rotations.
And now we can build up our styles that we return.
We're to return to image 1 and image to styling.
The first one for image one will just be a transform will pass and scale and we'll do image scale and
then image to where does your transform and two different transforms scale.
We have an image scale already which would be the exact same and then rotate image to rotate.
And so we're good to go for our screen styles now that we have that we can go apply them so we're going
to do a screen three styles will go down to our third screen which is right here and we'll pass in to
our first image which is our stationary one screen three Stiles image one for image to screen to style
the image too.
So will refresh this and take a look at our animations.
The first one we can see is translate X moving away.
And at the same time the screen to image to you is moving up and fading in and then we'll hit that input
range as we move away which will fade it out and up.
And as we move in we can see our scales happening that rotates happening and now we're completely scaled
in.
And then when we move over to potentially the fourth screen we can see that we have to find our fourth
screen and interpolate input range.
But we're not doing anything.
And that balance is just taking effect.
One thing I want to point out with the endings so screen 1 and screen 3 because we're using extrapolate
clamp and defining additional ranges then these won't continue using the default which extrapolates
which is for extrapolate is extend.
But if we remove this and this and then remove our our third parameter here and remove this because
the input ranges in output ranges need to be exactly the same now that we've defined this with the default
of extend we can scroll over to screen 2 and instead of defining the third operation book has continued
to scale larger here.
And then this will continue to rotate.
We can prove that here as you can see it scales up and rotates.
So unless you want the default to happen you'll need to find that last parameter in our input range.
Otherwise you'll get this.
And that may not be ideal for you.