This is the expanding right button that I saw on your movement.
If you check out the dribble by clicking on it here you just click on the image will pull up the dribble.
There's actually a demo so you can see the code and the demo for the web version of it and sometimes
people provide that.
But are going to recreate it in re-acting of using animated rather than CSSA transitions.
So let's take a look at first.
We have it already built here in animated.
But let's take a look at it actually being frame by frame.
So I download the Jif and I pop it open and sometimes you had you have to scroll through a lot of just
B.S. that isn't necessary to get to where the actual action happens.
But first off we start with the right button.
And as soon as we click we can see that it basically instantly disappears.
So there will likely be either an unmount there or some sort of opacity change.
Now stepping through we can see that the bar slowly starts to expand and you can just barely make out
the icon so there are going to be a switch some sort of switch between the right button and the icons
and this will slowly expand and it looks like these are covering each other but we can kind of take
care of that and eventually we will hit full bar expansion and we can see that now there is a bottom
there's a bottom that is already coming out so there wasn't here.
And then once this bar is fully expanded and the icons are basically fully transparent this starts sliding
down.
So in your head categorize and just you could even write these down the steps of animations that are
happening.
So we've gone from a visible word immediately gone to some sort of expansion and this could be either
a with or potentially a scale x then more opacity on new content in the potentially previous container
and now we have another animation here.
And basically it was a two step animation by the way so you can see that this does not start expanding
until we already have this bar expanded.
So in your head think about interpellation this is could be a reversal animation.
So from 0 to 1 and using a using a cliff we could prevent this from happening until this bar had completely
expanded.
So now we can scroll through these will scroll through frame by frame.
If you just scroll up and down and see that this basically by the second frame there was a start writing
so we are here.
And then we now have an input.
This is start writing keep scrolling and then eventually it's completely out.
So we don't necessarily need to go too much more into it.
We have our buttons kind of completely there.
We saw this expand down and then to do the reverse.
We would just run our version of animation backwards from one to zero and then we could slide this up
and then this would scale towards the middle.
Overall though it's important to see the animation frame by frame or to be able to have someone explain
it to you and categorize the types of animations because all animations are going to be a series of
either a layout change with width and height or it's going to be a transform or an opacity in those
transforms you have translates which are movement.
So if you see something that is moving position then it's likely to translate if you see something growing
then it's either with height modification or a scale x and y modification.
And then if you don't see something and then see something and then it's you know an opacity or if it's
rotating then it's a rotate.
So being able to kind of break down step by step each particular animation it's very helpful to have
it frame by frame.