Sometimes it makes sense to start with the ending of an animation and then work our way back to the
beginning view of the animation.
And that's what we're going to do for this evolving right button.
We're going to start by setting up some state and this will be a reversible animation so we'll just
have a single animated value that defaults to zero.
Now because this will be some sort of user input we're going to want to use a keyboard avoiding view
at least on iOS.
So I want to use keyboard avoiding view and we can use the behavior padding
and the keyboard avoiding view actually acts like any other view.
It's just a view that takes styling so we're going to give it some style and the styles of center and
this will be centered in the middle of our screen because our container is centered and then we want
to center the content that is inside of our keyboard avoiding view and this will allow us when we do
our animation to expand out from the center and I'll point that out again later.
So going to the center and just paste in a line item center and justify content center.
So the first thing we're going to do is set up an animated view that's going to wrap all of our content.
And this is just going to be our editor wraps or is an animated view style equals a array.
Because we're going to add some animation to this later.
Styles editor
and then close that off.
Now for our editors styling it's just going to be a simple border.
So we're going to create our editor
and then give it a border with one and then really give it to color and we're going to go R-GA 0 0 0
0 point 1.
Now that we have our editors set up we can start working on the two pieces at the end.
And those are the the bar that contains our buttons and then also our text input.
So we're going to go focus on the bar first and let's if we think about this the right button has a
blue background as well as the bar.
And if we're going to animate one away and one in so whether it'd mean the bar that the bar icons in
or the right button that means you can have the same blue background.
And because this is going to be opacity there that means you want to have a rapping view that has the
bar on it.
The bar blue bar color and then add additional content inside of it.
So we're going to set up a view that has styles up bar and this will be our rapping bar and then we
can start putting our other content in here including our toolbar of buttons and then our right button
as well.
So for our bar we need to just give it a height and a color and then will do height of 50.
So that will be the button height as well as the height of the bar background color of 2 9 7 9 f.f.
And then we'll do justify content Center and we'll fix our missing quote there.
So now if we refreshed this we can see that there is only the border that we have defined on our editor.
So now we should go and add our toolbar.
So inside of here because it's going to be animated because we need to adjust the opacity and faded
away it's going to be an animated view.
And we'll give it a style and because we animate it will do in a race who can pass in some additional
animated stuff later and give it styles that toolbar
and then we can start adding icons.
Now I'm just going to paste in our icons that we're working with for the left side.
And if we go ahead and refresh this we can see that we are in a column direction and we don't want to
be in a calm direction for our toolbar.
So let's go style our toolbar to make it correct.
So down here we can add our toolbar style and because you want to in a row we'll give it flex direction.
Rowe and to have some spacing on both sides of our toolbar.
We're going to give it a padding horizontal of 10 and because we want our items aligned in the middle
of the bar we'll give it a line items center
free special line items correctly and then we want to justify content flex start and that will have
our buttons that are the child of our tool were forced to start on the left side.
So we can see that we have some padding horizontal and our buttons are here and we'll see how we add
in our right to our next.
So our design constraints are that we have a set of buttons here that are forced to the left and then
another set of icons that are all the way to the right depending on the size of our bar here.
And so there'll be a gap here once our toolbar is fully expanded out.
So in order to do that we're going to need to create another view
and then add our icons in here and we're going to need to apply some styles to this which we'll call
styles that right in inner bar now will add our icons.
And then go style our right inner bar.
Refresh this without actually styling we can see that this is not what we want.
We have a row and now we are right in our bar which is a new view.
It is not a dot that Fox direction it's going to switch back to being a flex direction column.
So we need to then switch it to a flex direction row so it stays in a row.
We'll then give it a line items center so that it's centered and then most crucial will give flex and
tell everything to move towards the end and render there and move back towards the beginning of this
particular view.
So now if we refresh we can see that our buttons are rendering or this just not take up the appropriate
amount of space because this outside bar view is just arriving.
It's with from the inner content.
So now we need to go fix this so that it actually is the appropriate with that we want.
So we can actually adjust the bar correctly.
So the width of this is actually going to be based upon the width of the window.
So an essay contests
equals dimension's does get window.
And we're going to define that on our editor and we're going to say with is equal to with minus 40 and
we will need to interpolate on this later.
So this is going to be a temporary value.
So we refresh we can see that we have expanded our bar.
However this still is not correct because the view itself that we that we created the right inner the
right interview if we can get it the right inner bar view is only taking up this much space.
So now that we have a with Applied being comes on here and tell this right in to take up all the space.
Flex one.
And now that it's taking up all this space we can actually select that now because it's taking up all
of this space.
We now have a flex one or the flex and tells it to start down here.
Now that we have our bar all set up we just set up the bottom porch portion which is the insert text
input.
So we come back here we can set up a new animated view because this is this animated up view will be
will be what kind of slides up and creates that tuck in motion.
And then we need to set up a text input
and we'll give it a placeholder.
Start writing as we saw in the break down.
Well then give it a multi line support.
That way we can write on multiple lines.
Well need to get a ref to it that way we can focus on it and blur it.
Whenever we open or close the the editor will say this underscore input was input and then finally
we need to give it some styling and we're going to give it the style sheet absolute fill that way whenever
we apply a height to this.
This will cover it entirely and we can then animate this and this will continue to also adjust to the
height that this is.
So we can just give our animated view a height.
So with this style equals an array and say styles got lower view and then here come give our lower views
some styling and we'll just give it a height of 150 so now and refresh this.
See that we have our input rendering.
And this whole bottom section is 150 and then our editor border with border that we gave it is now showing
up.
Now this is touching the sides and we don't want our input to be touching the sides like that.
So we'll give our inputs some styling will say padding of 10 so it's padded all around and then a font
size of 20 just to bump up the writing because if we wrote on it now would be pretty small.
So if we come back here we can apply our styles the input refreshed this and now this has bumped up.
Type of a decent size and it's has some padding on the outside.
Now we have our whole thing set up.
This is what the ending state looks like.
So now we're going to go and render what the beginning state should look like.
And that's just going to be a right button that is on top of this bar.
So because we're rendering this bar here this toolbar here we need to render our right button inside
of our bar so that it will get this blue background.
And because we want to render it on top of this and we want these to still be intractable we're going
to need to use our pointer events technique which means we're going to do an animated view and style
it with a style sheet that absolute fill to cover and then we will close that off.
And then we will start setting up our button will do a touchable without feedback
and then simply just render some view a view and some text that says right and we will need to apply
some styling to this so we'll give it style equals style stop button text and style that in a second.
And then free refresh means that we are rendering our right button in the top left corner and we don't
want that we want it to be centered.
So were to come here and use the same center styling that we used before for this keyboard avoiding
view and just give it styles that center.
And now when we refresh we can see that this Riperton button is centered.
So now we can kind of grasp that there's going to be a transition happening.
This is going to be shrinking to a particular size and this Riperton will stay right in the middle of
all these disappear and then the reverse can happen.
This will disappear.
And these will expand out so quick styling on our button text will just give it a color of white refresh.
And now we're ready to go so for the first bit we need to kind of break down what this animation is
doing.
This is sliding up and then this will slide in.
So it is a two part animation.
However we will also be operating the other direction.
So we're going to start at the right button.
So we kind of need to do this slightly backwards.
So I'm going to remove this with here because the first thing that happens when we actually open this
button when we press on this button is that this width of our editor is going to expand.
So we're going to set up an interpolation for our editors who say conc with interpret state animation
interpolate we'll set up an input range of zero because we will start at zero and this right button
will be a particular distance or particular with and for half of the animation we want to expand.
So output range will be 100 and this will just be the width of that bar when nothing when the button
is closed or when the editors closed.
And then we'll do with minus 40.
Now these could be percentages or or whatever measurements that you have.
But this is styling for the whole screen right now and then because we are in a many to one and only
defining a half of the animation in our input range you want to do and extrapolate clamp.
And now we can go ahead and pass this value into our editor like we had before and if we refreshed this
we see that now we are starting to take shape of having that right button.
Now we have the right button.
The other content isn't hidden yet and the input is now smaller as well because we're affecting the
whole layout.
So still focused on this toolbar.
The thing that is happening is that these buttons are appearing and we don't want them to appear.
So let's set up some opacity for that so we'll say it's opacity toolbar.
Interpret this as state animation interpret and we'll do the same thing for the input range which was
zero point five an output range.
And when the button is close we don't want those icons to show up but after half of the animation we
do and we'll do an extrapolate clamp here as well.
And now we can craft our toolbar styles and passenger opacity with opacity toolbar inter-relate bring
these down here and pass them into our toolbar animated view.
And when we're refreshed we now have the first portion that we care about we have a right button and
now that we're working backwards we can see that the second piece that we need to take care of is is
making this collapse to zero.
So up here we can set up two interpretations.
One will be for the editor height so say Ed..
Interpret this to state animation and interpolate and we'll put the input range and we won't.
We need to do this second because remember the actual animation is click on the right button.
The bar will expand and then this will drop down and then the exact opposite will happen when we close
this is this will slide up and this bar will slide in.
So that means we need to do something in the later stages of the animation which is to say point seven
to one and then our output range will be 0 and 150 and then we'll also do an extrapolate clamp here.
So let's a justice to say Ed..
And now we can craft our editor styling so say editor style to opacity is that state animation will
just have it hidden and then we'll do height and pass an editor right.
Fix this say.
Spell it correctly.
And now we can take our editors style and add it to our lower view.
And now when we refresh we're back to where we want we have a right button that is just standalone and
the interpretations are set up to expand out and drop down.
However we don't have an interpolation yet to hide a right.
That's always going to be visible right now so let's go fix that.
So for our button to be hidden We need that to happen in the first half of the animation because as
we go moved towards zero to point 5 where our button icons are expanding we need that to hide now in
the actual animation.
It happened really quickly.
It was a very it was a single frame that that right would disappear.
But we're going to have it slowly disappear so we're into a conc opacity button interpolate.
So you go to this that state animation interpret passenger input range which be zero and point five
and because at zero because our starting animation we want the opacity would be one so you can see it.
And as it advances to opening EDR it'll editor disappear.
And then also extrapolate clamp here.
Now we can create our Konst button styles pass in our opacity and our pastie button interpolate and
then we can go and apply this to our button wrap here.
And now we have our interpellation is all set up and we can kind of see that if we go and adjust this
value here if we flip this to one and refresh we can see that we are the do the right buttons gone and
we are in our full editor position.
Unjustice to point five and see what the half mark looks like.
We can see that the bar is visible are right button is 0 is gone and we can kind of just step through
manually and see what position our transitions are happening at and that gives us a good feeling and
we can now go and actually execute a transition from one to 0 for our our right.
So let's refresh this back to 0 and on our right button with our touchable without feedback odd add
and on press and say this toggle transform and now we will go create a
toggle transform and the other portion that we will need to take care of is the pointer event.
So once this expands that right view is still going to be absolutely a position.
Now we could control it not rendering and rendering but we'll just use the pointer events technique
for now.
So for our two values they can't say to value is equal to this dot on the square.
Open and then do zero and one animated timing and or this state animation to value and then we'll just
do a duration of five hundred and fifty and then we'll call start.
And at this point we'll then toggle this open doesn't equal equals not just open.
And then we will also toggle a state value.
So we're going to add an open false to our state and then do this Dot said state and open this open.
Well just because we talk a here we can just keep doing it at state.
Once this animation is interrupted then this will get called if that's if that's possible.
So now if we refresh and we trigger our animation free press on right see that we expand out our right
fades away and then this bottom part expands but we don't have a way to close it just yet.
We don't have a way to close it but because we aren't toggling pointer events on a right button if we
press on this again we can see that our animation reverses
and we can fix that by coming down here to our covering view and just giving our pointer events.
And if it's open then there's none.
And then if it's not then it's odd.
So in this case it's not open so it's going to be auto Pressel once it's open and we won't be able to
click it.
Now the final important piece is the accessibility of focusing on the input or blurring the input.
When this right button closes because if you keep focus on the input we're not unmounting it.
And that means the keyboard will still show up even though this right button is closed.
So we're going to go here and say this that open and do it ternary because we haven't talked with it
yet.
This Open is going to be the state of the opposite state of what we're kind of talking about so if it's
open and this is called that means we're heading towards not open.
So this input Blair however if it was previously open we haven't really yet.
That means that for opening and say this stot input focus and now if refresh and open nothing happens
because we don't have a keyboard or press command OK.
And then we don't have a way to close it yet but if we keep our keyboard and we can see that once the
animation is done then we have our keyboard pop in and now we need a way to close this view and we can
do that with a close button or whatever you feel like doing.
I added this after the fact and we're going to paste this in.
It's called toggle transform because we're actually using the same toolbar styles which if we go look
at our toolbar styles is just an opacity this will fade in when the toolbar is visible and then fade
out when it isn't visible.
And now we need to just style or close button so that it will be a little more visible even though we
have our input here or our keyboard here.
We need to make this little more visible so you come down here and do close.
So we'll do two things.
We'll move it away from our editor and the keyboard and then give it some color.
So say color is this same thing that we have for our bar
and then Marjan top of 10 and margin
bought 20.
So now when we refresh can press on our right button expand our clothes will be visible and we can close
it.
And once that's closed in that blur is called and our keyboard will disappear.
So some kind of ending takeaways.
Sometimes it is easier to focus on the ending state first at the starting state and then slowly transition
each particular piece until you have the exact animation that you want.