Let's take a look at what we currently have set up we've got an animated view.
That's our motile instead of that we have a comment wrapping a scroll view inside of our scroll though
you have some fake text at the top.
We have fake comments in the middle which is just a view with a thousand pixels of height and some background
color.
And then we have some fake text at the bottom so they know that we hit the bottom.
Now in our component will now will create a few things.
The first will be this animated which is just going to be a new animated value that we control then
additionally will create this dot animated margin is a new animated value as well which will help us
add the crushing swipe down effect to our motile and then we'll also create this scroll offset this
Staat content.
And this scroll of view.
I will just initialize those all to zero Roughead and we'll set up our stylings for our animated values.
So I'll say conc spacer style is equal to margin top.
And then we'll just pass it on to this animated Marjan will then do a concert opacity interpolate and
will operate off of this to animated inter-relate So to take an input range because we can Faid going
both up and down.
We'll start our input range it's negative 400 0 and then 400 so that we can use the same opacity interplay
for both interactions and then our output range will be 0 1 and 0.
Now we can set up our model south so say conc modal style is equal to an object transform which takes
a translate Y and we'll just pass in this to animated so that we can control the swiping up and down
or moving our motile out of the screen.
And then we'll also apply our capacity here with our capacity.
Interpolate now set up our styles and apply them to our certain views so will create an animated view
here.
Say style equals our margin or space or style.
We'll then also add in our modal style to our modal also need to capture some of the data from our scroll
view.
So the first thing we'll do is add scroll event throttle and we'll set it to 16 milliseconds so that
we're notified every 60 milliseconds that a scroll happened in or on scroll of that callback will say
event and then will assign the properties that we set up above.
So this scroll offset will be equal to our event native event content offset that Y and then will say
this scroll view height is equal to or event need event to lay out measurements that height will also
get the content size of the entire scroll of view innards.
So say on content size change which will then receive the content with the content right.
However we currently only care about the height so say this content height equals content height.
Now let's go back up to our component will mount and will simply create a pan responder will assign
it to this not pan responder.
The pan responder will allow us to act on the gestures and when we want to start and stop them.
So first of all move the On-Star should set pan responder will focus on the move.
Only this will allow us to control when we want to start our takeover of the gestures.
So say Konst DIY which is our Delta y gesture state.
It we'll get a total scroll which is total scroll high which is a combination of this scroll offset
Plus this scroll view height.
Now we want to set up our conditions for when this pan responder should respond.
So we'll say if and our first will be this scroll offset.
It's less than equal to zero.
And our Delta Y is greater than zero.
This one is for when we are at the top and we are dragging downwards and we want to crush our mobile
out of the way.
The second one will be for when we're at the bottom and we're dragging up and we want to swipe it away.
This you can tell by saying total scroll height is greater than or equal to this stock content right.
And our D-y is less than zero.
In these cases we want to return true which will trigger our pan responder and allow us to interact
with the gesture.
Now it's set up when we actually do our move so we can delete the arm pan responded Grant and just deal
with our move say Konst do you I see call to are just your state and if our D-y is less than zero.
Will say this animated set value are D-y or Delta y otherwise OutServe fire D-y is greater than zero.
We just control our animated margins.
This animated margin not set value of D-y to make them work.
We need to go down toward motile and do our spread of this pan responder type panhandlers will spread
those on to our motile.
Now you can go ahead and refresher emulator and see that if we scroll down and once we get the bottom
we can swipe our moral away or scroll down and then come back to the top and drag down.
We can actually crush our modal.
Finally we need to control what happens when we release.
So we'll get our D-y from our just your state and if our Delta Y is less than 150 which is just an arbitrary
threshold it will do an animated parallel we'll say animated that timing on this animated will say to
value negative 400 which translate Y will make our our model go up in a duration of 150.
Then we'll also do an animated timing on this animated margin and we'll just animate that back to zero
of a duration of 150
that will set up our LCF for DUI is greater than negative 150 and our DeWyze less than 150.
We haven't gone anywhere outside our threshold so we'll do an animated parallel animated timing this
animated to value zero for the duration of 150 and then we're also animated timing this animated margin
to zero.
Duration 150 This will allow us to release and then go back to a neutral position.
Finally LCF our Delta Y is greater than 150.
We want to do an animated timing on this animated and in this case we're swiping down so we'll just
say to value of 400 and a duration of 300 milliseconds.
Now I also need to call star on all of these otherwise our animations won't trigger so we'll go call
start on our parallel and also cost on our parallel up here for a refresher emulator.
You can see that we can crush it and it will snap back or if we hit our threshold then it will zoom
away and fade out or we can scroll to the bottom once at the bottom we can swipe it away and it'll snap
back if you don't hit 150 or you can hit the threshold and zoom away.