Start by putting scroll view dimensions an animated film Riak native next will the structure of width
and height from a dimension stock get call which is a function that takes the winter window which will
turn the current dimensions of the phone screen.
Now Lego set up our state an acting structure pretty epic this state is equal to an object will create
an animated scroll state variable and assign a new animated value with the default value of zero.
Next inside of a container will create a scroll view close of our school you and all the properties
paging enabled which will cause this groovey just stop on multiples of it's with the horizontal flag
scroll event throttle to throttle our scroll event caused to 16 milliseconds and then at or on scroll
which will be an animated event which is a function that takes an array for grab native event the content
offset and the X of the content offset and assign that to this state that animated scroll.
Now it will create a new file which will call a moment.
Yes and inside of will create a new reac component and call it moment.
Now we'll go back to our app and we'll import our new file that we created.
Now go under scroll view and inside of it will do.
Images map which takes a function which will get our image and our eye will then return the moment file
that we created will pass and he for the index will spread our image so we'll pass on our properties
little clearer image and our title now switch over to our moment is that we created our import animated
dimension's and touchable without feedback.
Now we'll do the same as we did before and we'll say conc with
the structure our dimensions Dockett call with the window now could add new style sheets will say conc
styles equal style sheet does create a so-called container which will have with the height which are
the width of the screen and overflow hidden.
Now also create an image style which will add flex 1 and with set to know height set to know no set
up or component structure so open this and close it will give our out of you the style styles container
style that we created.
Now an animated image which will give the source of this stuff start image style will say styles image
and also will get the resize mode to sign cover.
So now I want to refresh your application.
You can see that images are finally loading and the paging is enabled
no dials for our title.
While at a center justify content value of center text draps style the background color of our G.P.A.
0 0 0 and in a passive.
Point five padding vertical of 10 and then our title text will be a background color of transparent
font size 30 color of white and we will line our text the center now go at our components so we add
a view and to give it a style and it be an array and a style sheet absolute fill which will add a left
0 0 top zero bottom zero with an absolute position.
So this will cover the image Well then at our styles data center inside of here will then add a view
and say style equals styles.
Text wrap and then inside of here will say text Well then you are this top prop's title.
And then we will add our style equals styles title and now in refresh we can see that the title of our
drink is in the middle of the screen in order to achieve our parallax effect.
We need to add a Konst animated style to be an object that transform key takes an array of transforms
and we use the translate X transform well passing this props that translate X we aren't passing down
yet.
And then we will add that to our image.
Now we'll move back to the index and we'll create a function which will call construct get interpreted
our function and will take the animated scroll the current index and the current amount of images that
we have now set up our interpellation will set apart input range will say conc input range is equal
to minus one times the width.
This will set up the translate X for the image before it is Swype to then will say I times with which
will be the translate X input for where we are at the image and then additional do I plus 1 times with
which will be the input range for after we have swept away from the image.
Now set up our conc output range and when we are at the first index we'll say 0 0 and then 150 translated
and then when we are anywhere else we'll say negative 300 which means that the image will be negative
300.
As we're swiping towards it it will then move toward 0 and then as we swipe by it it will be at 150.
Now will return animated skirl interpret will pass in our input range our output range and then extrapolate
clamp which means no matter what happens it will never go past zero negative three hundred or one half
or 150 on either side.
Now we'll go down for a scroll viewer rendering our moments will set up to translate X property that
we're using for animation we'll called Get interpret and pass and this state animated scroll will pass
in our current index and then we pass an image is length.
Now if a refresher emulator and we swipe we can see that a translate X effect is happening on both images
finally we'll go at a separator style will criticized called separator which will be a background color
of black position.
Absolute top zero bottom zero will give with a five scroll to the top and click Konst get separator
is equal to the current index which will turn a view which we will say is a self-closing view because
we're putting nothing in the middle.
We will give it a key of the current index and we'll say stout equals an array style start separate
and then we will say our left is I minus 1 times with minus 2.5.
This will cause our separator to be right in the middle of both images.
Now we need to render them inside of our scroll view which say re apply no say length is equal to our
images length plus 1.
This will create an empty array with the length of our images plus 1 in that so that our separator will
be rendered on the final screen as well.
Say map which will be an arrow function will put in something pointless here will get our index within
say arrow function get separator.
Will pass in our index and now refresh we can see that a black bar is rendered in between each of our
images.