Let's take a look at the current state of rap you have a constructor where we set up this state of hearts
with just an array.
We have a handle at heart function.
We have a touchable without feedback that call that function and we have a view where we can use the
stylesheet absolute fill which will do a.
Absolute position of left top right and bottom of zero.
So it covers the entire screen and then we have a heart.
This heart consists of a rapping view with two heart shapes and the heart is going to be 50 by 50 and
the heart shape will be 30 by 45 and the left heart is just a piece that has rotated negative 45.
And another piece that is rotated 45 degrees.
We're going to need the current dimensions of the screen.
We can get that same concert with height which will destructuring from the dimensions get window call.
Now down in our handle at heart said Konst animation is equal to a new animated Valin which was set
to zero.
This will create a new animation every time we want to and add a new heart next will call this that
sets date and because we'll be referencing state and we want to make sure that all of the states have
flushed through we'll pass a function into our state which will receive the state at the time that we
need it will then return a new object of hearts with our state hearts in it as well as an animation
that we just created and the start which will be a starting position along the bottom and we'll just
say get random inte 100 with minus 100.
Finally we need to start our animation so we'll pass in a second function here which will act as a component.
Did update we'll then get our animated timing and say animation which is the animation for this particular
heart that we just created so to value our height and then we'll say duration of 3000 and then we'll
call start on our animation.
What this will do is take our animation which starts at zero which is an asset and then animate it to
a value of the height of the screen.
So from the bottom to the very top now that we have our animations being added to an array when we press
stuff and started we don't need to render them on the screen so we'll create this state map the hart's
map which will take a function and we will structure animation and our starting position.
And we'll also get the index from here.
We return a heart just at the key of our index
the heart floating will consist of a series of animations.
The first one is a position animation so say conc position interpolate is equal to the animation and
one chirpily on it.
And so the input range is starting at zero and going to the height and we'll flip that around and say
height minus 50.
So it will start 50 pixels because from the bottom up because our heart is 50 pixels high and it will
go to zero.
We'll then go set up our style.
So we'll get conc heart style equal to transform and here will say translate Y and put in our position
and interpolate our second animation will be opacity.
So say conc opacity and chirpily is equal to animation and chirpily input range will be 0 to our height
minus 200 and our output range will be 1 to zero.
This will allow our opacity to start at 1 and as it goes up it will fade out to zero.
So we'll go ahead and add that to our style opacity and we'll set our opacity inter-relate the third
will be the scale the scale because our bubble to bubble up very quickly and start from zero and look
like it emerged on the scene.
So we'll do concert scale interplay.
So you can see our animation done Tripoli in the input range will be very quick will be 0 15 and 30
output range will be 0 1 point 2 and 1 and we need to set extrapolate
what this will do is within 30 movements we'll go from zero the heart grow to 1.2 times its size.
And then back to one if we did not have this extrapolate clamp it would just continue on scaling the
heart so well then add that to our transforms was a scale scale interplay.
The fourth and final will be a little wobble.
So first full divide we want six wobbles so say conc divided height is equal to our height divided by
6 Lynsay Konst wobble interpolate animation interpolate in our input range will start at zero and go
toward a valid.
Times 1 divided high temps two times three and a half times for height times.
Are divided high time six.
That means we need an output range so our output range needs to match the same amount as our input range.
So I would say zero and will go 15 to negative 15 and I'll just wobble back and forth between 15 and
negative 15.
So we have seven here including the 0 1 2 3 4 5 6 7.
And then here we will also add and extrapolate clamp
with this wobble and interpolate will apply that to the translate ex translate x.
Finally we want a random start position so say left and add in our start which is the random number
that we created in the beginning and now we can apply our style to our heart.
Now if we go and refresher emulator and we tap on the screen you can see it explodes from zero and scales
up and then floats and wobbles side to side.
We create a whole bunch of hearts just tapping on the screen.