We'll start by putting animated in touch but without feedback from Riak native knows Take a look at
how we're going to build our heart a heart will be a singular rapping view with two pieces that will
make up each side of the heart.
There's a generic Heart-Shaped and then in a left and a right heart piece it's the heart shape is a
with a 30 and a height of 45 that's positioned absolutely as a board or top left or radius and a border
top right radius which means the top will be rounded but the bottom will be straight.
Then for the left piece or the right piece we either rotate it 45 degrees negatively or positively cause
them to sit on top of each other to prove this pull out a background color to our left heart.
And now interview FRESH who can see that one piece of our heart exists.
Now if add the background color of black to the other and refresh and see now that the two pieces are
sitting on top of each other let's remove our background color and take a look at how we're going to
create a heart that looks empty because of how we've built this heart.
We can't use the normal border style to create an outline.
So instead what we'll do is we'll create another heart that has two pieces of heart that are white and
will absolutely position it and scale at 2.9 and you can see that here in our styles that we've skilled
at 2.9 and then we set them back on color to white when then we'll render it on top of and inside of
our current heart.
And that way it will look like there is a border so we'll render that.
Remove this Phil style.
And when we refresh you can see that there's a gray heart on the outside with a point nine scale white
heart on the inside.
Now that we have our heart rendering we can go back to our index and start setting up our bouncy heart.
The first thing we'll do is set up our state will create this state and will equal an object.
I liked to keep to keep track of whether or not we've pressed the button or not.
At a scale animation I will say a new element of value that we default to zero and then will create
an array of animations where all default them to zero.
And these will be the animations for the heart so will copy and paste this will create six different
parts.
Now we'll set up a trigger like function that will be called when our button is pressed and will also
bind it to this in our constructor.
Instead of our trigger like we'll call this that set state and Tugger like by saying not this dot state
DOT liked Now narrow scroll down to our heart and we'll wrap it in a touchable without feedback as well.
We'll add an animated view and we'll put this inside of the animated view at or on press which will
call this stuck trigger like.
And also to our heartwood filled equals this state liked now for your fresh and we go later and we press
the heart we can trigger it being filled in.
We want to add feedback to our heart.
So we'll say Konst bouncy heart
equals this state that scale doesn't interpolate which is a function that takes an object to the input
range is 0 1 2 in our output range is one point a one.
Now we'll set up our button style so say Konst heart button style equals an object and we'll say transform
an array at the scale transform.
Add in our bouncy heart we'll apply that heart button style to our animated these style equals heart
button style.
Now up in our trigger like we'll call animated spring and we'll do it on our state that scale animated
value will take a configuration object will say to value of two with a friction of three.
Then McCalls start on our spring animation we'll add a callback function to our start call which we
called when the animation is complete and we'll say this state that scale set value and we'll set it
back to zero so that we can reach spring the estimation if the button is pressed.
So now for a refresher emulator you press our heart we can see that it springs.
And then when we unpressed it it springs again.