We'll start by creating a style called Heart position.
Absolute top zero and left zero.
Now go create some parts.
So we'll start creating a heart adding and filled to true in style equals styles.
Will copy and paste this six different times.
Now go create a function which will call Konst get transformation.
Animation which will be a function
that takes an animation scale y x rotate and opacity.
Now we'll do a series of interpolations on the animation to create or effect.
Well first two scale animation and animation interpolate is a function that takes an object in an input
range will be 0 to 1 in our output range will be 0 to whatever the scale gets that gets passed and we'll
do our X as well so say concert x animation equals animation interpolate input range 0 to 1 and our
output range 0 to the X that gets passed in we'll do the same for R Y.
So we'll say Why animation instead and translate to our Y do the same for our rotation.
So say rotate animation.
However instead of 0 we will switch that to 0 degrees and then r rotate.
That gets passed in and finally we'll do our opacity animation.
So this opacity animation and will do it to the capacity that gets passed in all set up a return value.
So an object will say opacity and pass and opacity animation will then do our transform which is an
array.
I will take a series of transforms our first will be scale lets say scale animation.
Our second Oby translate X on passenger X animation.
The third will be translate Y or passenger y animation and the fourth will be rotate repassing or rotate
animation.
Now we'll go plier animations to our hearts.
We'll switch all of these over to being arrays
and then we'll add get transformation animation and inside of here we'll say this state animations 0
and we'll pass in our configuration stuff.
So say point eight negative 60 0 35 degrees and point out opacity because you other hearts will follow
the same configuration will just remove the five hearts and replace them with five of hearts we just
created.
Now when you do just each of these hearts to match the configuration.
So first we'll change these so that they are referencing different animations.
We'll change this to point three.
This one 2.3 this one point seven and this on the point for will change this one to negative 120.
This one to negative 150.
This one a negative 120.
This want to know over 120 and this one to negative 280 for X will change this one to negative 120.
This one too positive 120.
This one a negative 40.
This one to 40 and leave this one at zero and Farje agrees this will be negative 35.
This one will be negative thirty five as well.
It's only negative 45.
This will be positive 45 and this one will be positive 10 degrees.
Finally we'll change our opacities 2.7 point six point three point five point seven.
Now that we have our hearts set up let's configure our animation and trigger like you first need to
create Konst show animations which we start state animations map which will be passed in a function
which will give us looping over animations and will return animated thought spring animation.
To value one with a friction of four.
The same thing for a hide animation.
So copy this will say hide animations and will change to value to zero a duration of 50 and will changes
from animated spring to animated timing and then we'll do a reverse.
Our hearts hide in the reverse direction.
No coordinate our animations with our bouncing button will say animated up parallel which is a function
that takes an array of animations.
And we will delete this and paste or animated spring into here.
Parel will cause the rest of our animations to trigger at the same time so will then do animated that
sequence which will execute one animation one after another which is a function that takes an array
was the animated got staggerer 50 milliseconds and then do our show animations and then do an animated
delay which will pause for a hundred milliseconds before it goes on to trigger the next animations.
There was an animated Stiger again 50 milliseconds and trigger our hide animations that will call start
on this set of animations will then add back in our callback function and this is complete and say this
state DOT scale that set value to zero to reset our bouncing heart.
Animation and when we go refresh emulator and we press ENTER button you can see that our heart bounces
and hearts explode and retracked back inside.