Let's dive in and check the state of our application before we start styling it and making it look nice
we have an animated value as well as a boolean for success of true and false.
We have a handle press and we have a handle send Additionally we have a few conditional inputs.
If we're not successful we'll render a text input to surrender the Notify me text.
However we are successful.
We'll render a thank you message.
The first thing you do is create an interpretation on the width so that we can control it expanding.
We'll set up a concert with interpolate say this state and it may not interpret our input range.
We'll have a few key.
We'll have a few values zero point five and one this will give us three steps an output range of 150
150 and 300.
We'll then also add and extrapolate claim of
will then do cartes button wrap style with and then add or with it.
You can go ahead and apply that third button wrap refresh.
And now we have a default of 150 with on our button.
The input is currently visible so we need to adjust it so that it is scaled out of the way said Konst
input scale and.
Of this state and animate inter-relate
input range to zero point five point six.
So a three step in our output range of 0 0 and 1 will then set up input scale style which we have a
transform of an array with a scale and put our inputs Gaile interpret it in here.
Now we can apply that to our interpellation or to our input and now one refresh.
You can see that it is scaled.
All of our stuff out of the way
now we not only need to scale our input but all seem to scale in our center but it's been come up here
and create a contest send button and interpolate.
It was this that state and a make inter-relate and our input range will be slightly shifted because
we want it to animate in after our input scale our input has scaled and so will say input range and
we'll set to zero point 6 and 1 in our output range be zero zero and then 1.
So it'll come in late.
So now we can go ahead and set up our contest send button style and do a scale as well.
And then we'll apply that to our Send button.
And finally before we can actually see this in action we need to create a scale for our notify me button.
So we'll say notice Konst notify text scale and interpolate we'll set up this state and interpolate
and this we need to scale out quickly before we scale and anything else will say our input range is
a two step of zero 2.5 or output range is 1 to zero and we don't want to scale any further so I will
say extrapolate clamp.
Now we'll go ahead and set up comments notify text sound and this will also be a skill so it transform
scale.
Pass this and then we can apply this to our animated view that surrounds our text so he calls high tech
style.
Let's go to the input scale inter-relate and we will add an extrapolate clamp so that it does not scale
beyond blunt one and now we'll go up here and say animated that timing.
So this state animate two value of one or duration of 300 milliseconds and then we'll call start.
So now when we press this button our input expanded focused and our button scaled in the final scale
will need as far I think you message we want it to scale in as everything else is scaling out.
So all do is set up of conc think you scale interpolate because this state enemy bullit and with our
input range will go from zero to 1 in our output range we'll flip that around and go one to zero.
This will cause a reverse effect.
So once this is animating backwards from 1 to zero to reset our scale will go from zero to 1 and it
will look like our think is animating in.
So say Kotz think you text style to transform with a scale or think scale and interpolate.
And we will go apply this to I think you textes.
Now when we press the send button handle send will be called so let's implement handles send.
We need to call this state and say success is true.
This will allow our Think New Message to be shown.
However it will be scaled out to zero because our animated value is all the way to one at the moment.
Then to scale everything out we'll do an animated sequence.
And in there we'll say animated timing this does state animate to value of zero.
Duration of 300 will also do a delay of animated delay of 5400.
Before we toggle everything back MacColl start start takes a function that will be called once this
animation is over.
And at that point you can then say this Utset state success false to reset everything back to the beginning.
So now we refresh click Notify type in an email click send.
Everything expands back to nothing and then resets back to the Notify me.