Opacity is used to control the visibility of a particular element it helps with a gradual entrance and
gradual exit to prevent any sort of jarring lay movements that may affect the user negatively.
We'll start with setting up a touchable without feedback which we've imported from re-act native and
we've also imported animated in order to use animated styles.
We need to use animated view as opposed to a regular view.
The enemy that you just wraps a regular view and so you can use all of the normal properties that you
would on a typical view that are documented and react needed.
Additionally our styles are container and box a container is a flex one which is just wrapping container
that will center items vertically and horizontally.
And our box is just a width and height of 150 with a background color of tomatoes that we can see it
to start.
We're going to create an animated value on our state.
Now you don't necessarily have to put this on state.
It can be put anywhere on this particular component instance.
But for the sake of this demo we would be putting it on stage.
So we will create a state variable called animation and we'll create a new animated value.
And because we're going to be controlling the opacity we want the default opacity to be 1 rather than
0 otherwise it would start hidden.
And now we'll create a dynamic style you'll need to create a dynamic style which is just an object because
we are referencing something that is on state or some other instance.
So if we say Konst animated styles which will be of variable name we'll then say opacity because that's
how you control the opacity of a style and then we'll simply pass in this state to animation.
Now we need to apply this particular style that we've created to our animated view.
So in order to apply multiple styles to a particular view we use the syntax array syntax.
So now we are applying our enemy and it's tied with the opacity that is driven by this state to intimation
and default to one to our enemy to view.
So one of the fresh this the opacity will still be one of our view.
Now you can see here are touchable without feedback is calling this start animation.
However we don't have a star animation function so let's go ahead and create that will create a star
animation and use the class property syntax because that's the default re-act native Babel plug in.
And this will allow us to bind this particular function to this instance every single time.
And that way when when it's bound to this particular instance that means we use this at state and or
anything else on this that we need to now use one of the animated functions which will be animated.
Timing it means that timing will specify the animation of a single value to another value over a set
period of time.
So its function signature is animation and then configuration object.
So in our case we want to say this state animation and then will provide an object and we'll say to
value of zero over a duration of 350 milliseconds in order to start an animation.
You need to call start.
And so now if we refresh and we have our touch with that feedback and we click on our box it will fade
out because it caused certain animation this animation will then be animated to zero over 350 milliseconds.
And in our case we're passing the entire capacity which is then being passed into our enemy to view
box.
Now let's take a look at our animation again what we call start will enemy everything away.
However when we pass in a callback to our start function it will get called when the animation is completed.
So once this reaches zero in 350 milliseconds this function will be called.
This then allows us to do other things like other animations or control some sort of set state and in
our case what we're going to do is animate the same exact this just to animation.
But we're going to animate it back to one.
So we use animated timing again passing this state to animation another configuration object.
And in this case because we've animated our value to zero.
We're going to animate it back to one and do it over 500 milliseconds.
And then once again we're going to call start.
So now if we go into fresher's simulator we can see that we have our box back and when we click on it
and get away and then immediately come back because the animation is completed and then animated it
back to one.