In some cases you may need to move items across the screen whether it be in a drag or just animating
them across a screen before they disappear.
The appropriate way to use to do this is to use translate.
It operates the most performance without also affecting layout.
We're going to start by setting up state again and say animation is equal to a new animated value and
we're going to set it to zero so that our translate does not start anywhere and does not offset our
particular view.
We'll then set up our dynamic styles so say Konst animated styles is equal to an object to do a translation.
You need to use the transform style and the transform style takes an array of different objects and
each object should have a key.
And in our case we'll use translate Y and we'll pass in this state to animation we'll then pass our
animated styles into our animated view.
And we see here we have our array syntax set up so we can combine multiple styles and then finally we'll
switch or start we'll create our start animation
and will once again use animated talk timing say this outstate animation to value of three hundred a
duration of fifteen hundred milliseconds and then we'll call start.
So now when we refresh and we press on our box we can see that it animates 300 pixels down translate
uses a grid where the 0 0 is the starting Top left point of the particular element.
So when you animate the y value 300 positive it will go down.
And if you were to translate X it would go from left to right in a positive fashion.
So we'll try that we'll switch or translate y to translate X and then we press this it will translate
300 pixels to the right off the screen.
Now switch this back to translate Y.
And in order to make this item go up we need to change this value to negative 300 so positive values
will go down for the translate Y and for translate X they will go from left to right and then if you
do a negative value it will go up.
So let's refresh this and animate from zero to negative 300 and you can see that now our box goes up
rather than down.
Now we'll switch this back to just 300 and we'll then pass our finish callback function into start and
then rather than animating we'll just say this state animation value of zero and that way we won't do
any sort of timing animation.
We will just literally set the value back to zero.
So once this hits the end it'll just reset right back to where it was to be being press on this and
it jumps right back.