Skill is a way to control the size of a particular element without actually controlling its layout.
Additionally scale can be used for other things like flipping items over on a reflection point to start
we'll create our state and create an animation and create another enemy to add value because the zero
scale would be non-existent.
The item would not appear on our screen will default one because that is going to be what scale defaults
to meaning it's just going to be a normal size of whatever the layout defined for then go set up Konst
animated styles and scale is going to be another transform objects will say transform which is an array
and pass and scale and say this Stut state animation and then we'll pass our enemy of styles into our
box.
And then create our start animation function for our touch without feedback and we'll say animated timing.
And so this state animation set to value of two.
So basically I will double its size say duration of 1300 milliseconds and then call start and now when
we refresh and we press on our box you can see that it grows to twice the size.
Besides growing larger scale also allows you to only scale the x value.
So if we refreshed this we can scale just horizontally or if we switched to scale why
it then scale vertically.
We'll flip this back to Y and change this to negative 2 rather than 2.
Additionally.
And some text inside of our animated view.
So I'll say this side forward
and then we'll also have to close our animated view.
So now enter refresh we will have some text inside of it.
However because we're animating to negative to what's going to happen is this is going to animate out
and then reflect and be the opposite direction.
So we press this is now flipped upside down.
This works for both scale x and scale y.
So if we change this to scale x we can see that it does a flip card animation to two times the size
but reversed.
Same goes for scale Y when we refresh it or flip over its horizontal axis and then all be scaled to
two times its size.
But in reverse.