Sometimes you need to estimate the width and the height of a particular element.
This will cause layout changes to happen for that particular element as well as any surrounding elements.
We have a box that is width of 150 and height of 150.
So we're going to say state equals animation create a new animated value and we're going to default
250 will then create animated styles and say with is the cause of this state animation as well as height
is you input of this state to animation particularly animations animated values can control more than
one property at the same time.
So he can pass in any minute styles to our animated view because we're now passing and animated styles
and defining the default value in this dynamic styles.
That means we can technically remove the width and height definition from our box as it will be overridden
by the animated styles because we've put that second.
So now onery fresh we can see that nothing has actually changed.
And now we'll create our start animation function and then say animated timing pass in this state animation
see to value of 300 and then pass in our duration of 1100 milliseconds and then call start.
So now when we refresh and press on our box it will grow width and height at the same time.
However if we were to remove one of these nothing would happen because we have removed the defaults
here so we'll move this and say height of 150 static and then we can just grow with end or alternatively
if we switch these we could also just grow right and back with in height that are both animated and
will show that this actually affects layout.
So we're going to add some text to the child of the box.
So now we're in refresh we can see that we have some text here rendering inside of our box.
And then when we animate it we can see that this text is going to reflow because the width of our box
is growing.