Absolutely positioning items we'll take it out of the normal flow of a particular view.
So in this case we've positioned it at left and zero.
However we have a container that says a line items to the center but it is not respecting that because
it is absolutely positioned
Typically you'd want to use translate to move things around the screen because it's going to be more
performant but in some cases you may need to use absolute position.
So we'll start by setting up our state with an animation and this time we will set it to zero as our
default will then say Konst animated styles and we'll say top is this state animation and we're also
control the left which is this does state that animation will then pass in our enemy and tiles into
our animated view.
Because we are controlling that we don't necessarily need this left and zero top inside of our styles.
However we will leave it just for examples later well then go ahead and set up our start animation and
say animated timing.
Sequel to this state animation and we'll say to value of 300 over the duration of fifteen hundred milliseconds
and then call start.
So now when we refresh this and when we press on our box you can see that it translates at this are
absolutely positions at the same time it animates from 1 0 0 to 300 on both top and left.
If we were to move one of these for example or for your move top it would just animate left.
And same goes for left.
We'll just animate the top.
Let's bring back our left.
And you can additionally animate more than just top and left.
For example if we were to remove the width here and set right of zero and animate rather than 300 to
40 and then pass in.
Right.
This state animation when this animation happens what's going to happen is this is going to take up
the entire screen because we set it at top left right zero with a height of 150.
But then it's going to animate to 40 in from the left and from the top and from the right at the same
time.
So you press this and see that we can both animate the left top and right at the same exact time.