Animated allows us to also use interpellation to control colors whether it be back on colors or text
colors.
We're going to start by setting up state is equal to animation and our new animated value.
And we're just going to it to zero then we're going to come down to our render function and we're going
to first set up our box interpellation that will be a box that you currently don't see because it doesn't
have a background color.
So it's a contest box interpellation is equal to this state animation.
Inter-relate and they will take a configuration object configuration object takes a few different properties.
The first one is input range this input range is going to be an array.
And it requires items to be in order so 0 to 1.
And this is defining a range of our animation.
So when you have zero there will be a direct correlation.
And when you have one there will be another direct correlation.
However it will figure out when the animation is between 0 and 1 what color to pick in it does that
by using the output range which also takes an array and we can pass in our colors.
This is our tomato color.
However interplay only works with our G-B our DPA and other various items.
But everything but Hexe but interpolate actually does returns a new animated value.
However when the value is requested by the animated view it'll figure out what color or what output
range it actually needs to be.
So in this case we'll set up a contest box animated style and say background color and we'll pass in
our box interpellation.
Then take our box animated style and apply it to our view.
And now when we refresh we can see that the default value is zero which then hits this particular input
range and output this particular color which happens to be tomato.
We then pass a background color and into our enemy to view.
And here we are now styling our background color.
You can interpolate more than once on this same animation.
So we're going to say Konst color interpellation or this state animation inter-relate which then will
take our input range of 0 and 1 and then an output range.
And in this case we're going to do the reverse so we're going to do the other color here and then trend's
interpret to our tomato color this color interpellation will then be passed into our Konst text animated
style and say color pass and our color interpretation then we'll take that and put it here.
On our animated Texas style is equal to Tex animated style.
So now one refreshed we can see that we have a tomato background with a purple interior color.
And now we're ready to go set up our start animation Well then say animated timing pass in this state
to animation.
So to value of one over the course of 1300 milliseconds and then call start
now when we refresh and we press on our box you can see that it transitions from blue to orange and
then if we enter a back and say animated timing state to animation to value of 0 rather than one over
the course of 1300 milliseconds and then call start refreshed this press.
You see that goes one way and then comes back.
This shows that over the course of this animated timing this value of this state's animation that we're
interpretating on is not always going to be exactly zero or exactly what it's going to be a range and
interpolate takes the output ranges and the values that are in between 0 1 and then figures out the
exact color that it interprets to.
And it does not matter which direction that this is animating as we can see that it happened both going
forward to one and backwards to zero.
It will only just figure out between these two ranges and does not care about which direction the animation
is occurring.