Animation also allows us to use interpellation to rotate a particular element using degrees or radians.
We already have our animated value set up so we can just use it.
Now suppose a contest rotates interpret does this start state animation inter-relate which takes an
object in our input range and because we are starting at zero that's our default here in our animation
will say zero.
And then we will say our animation will run to 360.
We'll then define our output range of rotation and say zero degrees rotated to start all the way to
three hundred and sixty degrees will then create our style so say Konst animated styles.
We do transform which is an array of transforms.
And in our case we'll say rotate and pass in our rotate interpret and then we'll pass in this to our
box.
And now when we refresh we can see that nothing has changed because our default values zero into our
internally input range and says output of 0 degrees which is no rotation at all.
We'll set up our start animation and say animated timing and say this state animation it's a to value
of 360 because that's what we have to find here.
Over the course of fifteen hundred milliseconds and then we'll call Start now and refresh.
We can press this and see that it spins 360 degrees over the course of fifteen hundred milliseconds.
Rotate also has a rotate X which will cause it to flip over the horizontal axis and then also rotate
Y which will cause it to flip over the vertical axis will changes back to rotate and you'll see that
this goes to 360 degrees which means that our rotation goes in a clockwise fashion.
If we want to animate it in a counter-clockwise fashion we can say negative 360 degrees and interpret
it or figure out that this needs to go towards the negative direction.
So you're fresh.
And now we will spin the opposite direction these values don't have to be exactly the same.
They could be just loosely correlated and interpolate will figure them out.
For example if we wanted to say 10 180 degrees here.
So it will spin a few times.
It will then spin a few times over the course of 2500 milliseconds so we press this and we see that
it spins very quickly.
Additionally we could cut this in half and say 180 degrees.
And in this case it would only spin half way.
Even though our input ranges 360 the interpreter will figure out the output range based upon the input.