Percentage with based lay out options like using with 20 percent and high of 20 percent in this case
we're not at it until later in re-act native.
And that was because of the additions to yoga.
However interpolate did not need to be fixed to be able to interpret the width and height with animated.
We already have our animated values set up so we'll say Konst with interpret as you get to this state
animation interpret and input range will just be 0 to 1.
But our output range will be 20 percent that will be our default to start to 50 percent of the width
and then we'll set up our Konst height and interpolate So this state animation inter-relate input range
of zero to one in an output range of 20 percent to 30 percent.
And now with our interpretations we will build out our enemy cells so we'll see conc animated style
sequel to with passing or with interpretive and height height inter-relate and then pass that into our
box.
And we already have width and height of 20 percent done here.
However we don't need that anymore because we have defined our percentages inside of our tribulation
and inside of this dynamic style.
The reason that we're not animating to the exact values is because these width and height percentages
are of width and height.
They are different.
So this is 50 percent of the width.
And this will be 30 percent of the height.
We'll start by now setting up our star animation with our animated timing and say this animation to
value of one over 2300 milliseconds and then we'll call start.
And now when we press on it we can see that it grows to 50 percent width and 30 percent of the height.