Generally animated runs on the javascript's side Halvard that means that if there is a lot of javascript
processing happening that your animations may not run at 60.
Yes.
However recently they've added the ability to run some animations on the native side including transforms
and opacity over things like background color and anything that runs through layouts so absolute positioning
or width and height will not be able to run using the native driver.
So let's do a comparison of using the native driver versus not used in native driver.
So here we have an animation and we're not using the native driver we have it commented out.
So impress on it will translate to 300 and we'll jump back to zero with the set value and then we can
enable our use native driver.
Save that and refresh chigger animation again.
And it's basically the exact same animation without really anything different.
However if we remove our unit of driver and we pay some code in time out we'll basically trigger 500
milliseconds into our animation and we'll just do a loop.
So we will block our javascript's thread.
So with our animated running on the javascript side this will block it from being able to do any of
the animations.
So if refreshed this and run it we see that we get stuck and then we'll jump back at some point once
this is actually completed.
However if we flip on our used native driver refresh we can see that this loop is still here and still
run.
However animation will actually continue to run throughout the entire loop because it is running on
the native side.
This also works with spring.
If we remove our duration and pass in spring here refresh and trigger animation we can see that our
spring animation ran on the native side because we still have our while blocking blue.
There's one other option that use native driver works on and that is animated event when it is passed
into a scroll view.
So let's switch over to our command line and do a get reset button as hard and then check out scroll
native
particularly could or could we can see that we don't have any animation that we are triggering but we
are passing an animated event into our onze girl that takes the Y content OFSAA and passes it into this
outstay animation.
Typically you would not define a second parameter to this animated event but you can see that we have
used need of driver being passed in as the second argument and the other thing to note is that we would
typically say Scuola throttles 16 and that's if it's running on the javascript sides of that we're notified
every six Tomales seconds that a scroll event has happened.
However in the case of animated event with a used native driver we want to specify one so we can capture
as many events as we possibly can.
So here we have our interpellation from 1 to 0 so we can pass it into our opacity.
We just set our back on color to meet a red color refreshes and we scroll we can see that our opacity
is changing and it's running on the native side.