The enemy that parallel function allows you to animate multiple animations at the same time we're going
to demo this by setting up two separate animations.
One is the color animation which we will default to 0 and the second is a scale animation for the color
animation we will use inter-relate.
So we really animating from 0 to 1 which means our color will start at this tomato and transition to
a purple as it gets closer to 1 and then additionally we will just pass in the scale animation to the
scale and apply it to our box.
In order to do this we would potentially have to say animated timing and then say this state that color
animation Hassen are configuration objects so to value of one and then a duration of 500 milliseconds
and then we would call start here.
Additionally they would say animated that timing at state scale animation or configuration object will
say to value of two and then a duration of 300 milliseconds and then call start.
Now this would theoretically work and we can show that off we press it and its scaled to two times the
size and also change purple.
But these are running at different times and we may want to only know when both of them are completed
and thats where the enemy the parallel helps helps us out.
So rather than calling start on both of these we will remove the start calls.
We will say animated parallel the enemy is up there will receive an array of animations that we should
execute.
So we will put these inside of an array.
And then we'll need to put a comma here.
So we have an enemy the timing here animated that timing here and it's inside of an array that we're
passing to intermediate parallel and rather than calling start on both of these animated timings we
will call start on the animated parallel.
Now what that's going to do is it's going to kick these both off at the same time.
And then this start callback will not be called until both are completed.
So even though this animated timing is going to be completed first because it is being executed quicker
it will not fire until this one is completed.
So let's just check this out.
Refresh press on it.
I mean see that the exact same effect happened with our enemy that parallel uncoiling start and then
to prove that this is not being called until our 500 second animation is completed we'll put a call
back here and just use the alert animation complete
we will refresh this and we can see that everything was completed.
The scale had been completed and it was transitioned to blue completely before our alert happened.