Animated sequence allows us to call animations in a line one after the other.
So in our case we're going to have a color animation and a scale animation.
They are going to use inter-relate and we're going to go from our tomato to a purplish color and then
additionally we're going to scale our box out.
So the equivalent of doing an animated sequence with how to sync with us would be to do an animated
timing and say this state color animation and our two value will be one and then duration of five hundred
milliseconds.
The MacColl start here and then because it's going after the animation with a start and then animated
timing just at state DOT scale animation which will go to a value of two and a duration of 300 and then
more calls start.
So now if we were to refresh this and press on our box would turn blue and then scale up.
So now with animated sequence we can remove all of this weird nesting.
And so we can switch this to animated that sequence.
And just like others we will pass in an array of animations.
And we will then put our enemy in the timing of our skill animation there and we'll close this off and
then we'll just call start on our enemy in sequence.
And so this will wait for this to be completed first and then it will execute this and then our start
callback will be complete will be called.
And so once again we can refresh this press on it and see that this accomplished the same exact effect.