The animated Stiger function allows you to execute animations but with a delay of a certain amount of
milliseconds.
So we will stagger it color and scale animation will say animated stagger and staggerer is different
than others and it takes a millisecond count first and then the set of animations that you want to execute
second so will wait 200 milliseconds and then define our array of animations will define our color animation
first.
They animated that timing that state duck color animation to value of one with a duration of 500 milliseconds
or second animation will be our Gale animation says the animated timing that state that scale animation
to value to the generation of 300 milliseconds and then we'll call start on our stagger now because
we are executing this one first.
We then wait 200 milliseconds.
We then execute this second one which is 300 milliseconds.
So this one will actually complete the scale will complete at the same time as the color animation does
because its delayed 200 milliseconds on a stagger.
So when we refresh this we will press that and see that they are staggered and complete at the same
exact time.