The animated delay function allows us to add a millisecond delay in between a sequence or a chain of
animations which means it can only be used with a series of animations like sequence parallel or staggerer
to use it.
We need to find a sequence of animations.
So say animated that sequence which will then take an array of our animations will say animated that
timing which trigger this state color animation to value of one the duration of five hundred milliseconds.
Well then say animated timing for this state scale animation so the value of to the duration of 300
milliseconds.
So this will cause our animation to change colors and then also scale up well then to an animated delay
of 1300 milliseconds.
So if we just call star on this refresh we can see what happens this fall.
Both do a sequence of timing So first this one and then this one
the start function would then be delayed 5400 milliseconds while we waited for this animated delay to
happen.
However there's other things that you could potentially do.
You could then use something like an animated parallel or some other sequence to animate more animations
or the same animations back to its starting position.
So in our case we'll do an animated parallel and that will take an array within the animated timing
and color animation to value of zero which was the starting position with a duration of 500 milliseconds.
And then we'll also do our animated timing of this state scale animation to value of one the duration
of 300 milliseconds as well.
See here we have a delay in between these two that executed one after the other and then another series
of animations that will then execute at the same time.
So if we refresh this you see that this will then wait for 200 milliseconds and then do the these two
animations in parallel.